<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cursory remarks upon some late disloyal proceedings in several cabals composed of an intermixture of interests</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 195 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 32 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A35509</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">9790738</idno>
  <idno type="VID">44100</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248503556</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing C7687</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R27280</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">09790738</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A35509)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 44100)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1354:6)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Cursory remarks upon some late disloyal proceedings in several cabals composed of an intermixture of interests</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 66 [i.e 58] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1699.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">William --  III, --  King of England, 1650-1702.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1689-1702.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-02 </date>
            <label>John Latta </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-02 </date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="summary_of_contents">
            <pb facs="tcp:44100:1"/>
            <head>THE CONTENTS.</head>
            <p>A Premonition against Causeless Fears; by shewing the Great things, the King and the Government has done for <hi>England;</hi> and the Ungrateful Returns His Majesty has Incountred from a Mixture of Various Interests, Assembled at several Cabals; compos'd of</p>
            <p>Old Jacobites, Republicans, False Friends, New Converts, Place-Mongers, Envious and Ambitious Murmurers, Seditious Clubbers and Writers; Who are continually</p>
            <p>Undermining Royal Authority, Reviling the Publick Ministry, and Raising Causless Jealousies and Suspicions, to amuse the People, and Advance themselves into the Supremacy, by False Notions in Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
            <p>Which are examined and Refuted: Their Suspicions prov<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Groundless: Their designs plainly discovered, in contributing toward the Disbanding the whole Army, Sending away the <hi>Dutch</hi> Guards, Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluding Members of Parliament, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And the Ways and Means by which they Promote Discontents, are Detected, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:44100:1"/>
            <p>CURSORY REMARKS Upon some LATE <hi>Disloyal Proceedings,</hi> IN SEVERAL CABALS: Composed of an Intermixture of INTERESTS.</p>
            <figure>
               <p>
                  <list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Engl.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Scotl.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>France</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Irel.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </p>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed in the Year, 1699.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="preface">
            <pb facs="tcp:44100:2"/>
            <head>PREFACE TO THE READERS.</head>
            <p>'TIS Notoriously known, to the Grief of <hi>Good</hi> Subjects, and the Shame of <hi>Bad</hi> Ones, that the King's Majesty, at several <hi>Cabals,</hi> has been Treated with less Honour and Respect, than is due to His Illustrious Merits, and Glorious Atchievements: Or, that becomes a People, whose Vast Obligations to Him, should have better Instructed them in their Duty.</p>
            <p>But since Scandals will arise; to prevent the <hi>Woes:</hi> that attend the <hi>Inventers</hi> and <hi>Promoters</hi> of them, I have essayed to put a Stop to their Currency, by en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavouring to Reclaim the <hi>Traducers,</hi> and Disabuse the People, who are imposed upon by <hi>False Suggesti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons,</hi> and attempted to be Frighted out of their <hi>Alle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giance,</hi> with feign'd Fears and Dangers.</p>
            <p>This being a kind Office to all, none can be dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pleas'd at the Ʋndertaking. For tho' I shew how the Nation is Abused, by Misrepresentations of Men and Things, I name not the Persons, and if any are so fond of discovering themselves, by being concern'd at Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Reflections, and say, <hi>There the Author meanes
<pb facs="tcp:44100:3"/>us,</hi> I cannot help it, <hi>They are in the Right,</hi> and I can only say, <hi>What made them there,</hi> they know themselves, and I my own meaning; which I take to be so <hi>plainly</hi> express'd, that no <hi>English</hi> Man can doubt of it, or think I have <hi>Usurp'd</hi> a Province I had no Commission for.</p>
            <p>If Men will do things they are unwilling to <hi>hear</hi> of, and raise <hi>Spectrums</hi> they are afraid to <hi>See,</hi> the Fault's their own. They that makes the <hi>Clamour</hi> must not blame the <hi>Eccho.</hi> Nor they that Raise <hi>Evil Spirits,</hi> be Angry at him that <hi>Laies</hi> 'em.</p>
            <p>Some Men have taken the Freedom publickly to Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>front, Scandalize and abuse Authority, and if Others may not have the Privilege of Vindicating <hi>injur'd</hi> Inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cency and Integrity, and of throwing the Calumnies up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the <hi>Heads</hi> of the Agressors, the Case is very hard, and admits of greater Aggravations, by reason their Cause is juster; for if such a Course must carry it, the Liberty we have so long and <hi>earnestly</hi> contended for, is all <hi>Chimaera,</hi> whilest every Man hath not an <hi>equal</hi> share in it. And therefore since it can't be suppos'd, that any Law of <hi>Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, Conscience,</hi> or of the <hi>Nation</hi> can be violated, by an honest Design of continuing a <hi>Right</hi> Ʋnderstanding, and a <hi>mutual</hi> Agreement, between the Royal Head and Loyal Members, by removing the Cause of Dissention, I shall not be in pain about the Contents of the ensuing Pages.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="treatise">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:44100:3"/>
            <head>CURSORY REMARKS, Upon some Late <hi>Disloyal Proceedings,</hi> &amp;c.</head>
            <p>THE Affairs of this <hi>Sublunary</hi> World, carry a Resemblance with those of the <hi>Air;</hi> for as in those <hi>Celestial</hi> Regions, there is sometimes a Sweet and Harmonious Concord, and Serenity through the whole <hi>Hemisphere,</hi> and at other times the <hi>Face</hi> of Heaven is overcast with Frowns, Fogs, and Exhalations, which hover a while in the <hi>Air,</hi> and at length break into dreadful <hi>Fulgura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions,</hi> and raise a kind of <hi>War</hi> in the Elementary World: So it is in this <hi>Inferior</hi> Orb, which is Peopl'd with Men compounded of the <hi>Elements:</hi> Sometimes we have gentle Calms of of <hi>Peace</hi> and <hi>Tranquility,</hi> and other times nothing but <hi>Wars, Seditions, Heats</hi> and <hi>Animosities,</hi> which like the Plague Infect our <hi>Conversations,</hi> di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sturb the Body Politick, and put all things out of <hi>Order.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And as the <hi>Commotions</hi> in the Sky are ingendred of Fogs and Mists, drawn out of Fenny and Diseased <hi>Commons,</hi> and are usually foreshewn by <hi>Rowling</hi> Clouds, and the Malevo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent <hi>Conjunctions</hi> of <hi>Erratick Stars;</hi> so the Troubles of the World in <hi>Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral,</hi> and of <hi>England</hi> in <hi>particular,</hi> take their Birth and Nourishment from Ill Humours that possess <hi>Ambi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tious</hi> Minds, and <hi>Indigent</hi> and <hi>Male<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>contented</hi> Men, who Aspire without <hi>Desert,</hi> Rail without <hi>Reason,</hi> and would put the Kingdom into a <hi>Flame,</hi> to warm themselves by the <hi>Heat</hi> on't: Or by dispersing their <hi>causless</hi> Fears and Jealousies through the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, <hi>design</hi> to Divide and Destroy it.</p>
            <p>We are fallen into those <hi>Dreggs</hi> of Time, wherein Atheism and Irreli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion, Sedition and Debauchery, seem to divide the World between them; wherein <hi>True</hi> and unaffected Piety is out of Countenance; wherein all the <hi>Sacred</hi> Tyes to our Sovereign, are as <hi>Loose</hi> as our Manners; and in which that <hi>Generous</hi> Honesty, and <hi>Religious</hi> Loyalty, which was once the <hi>Glory</hi> and <hi>Character</hi> of our Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, is <hi>vanish'd</hi> into Disobedience and Contempt of our Superiors: For a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:44100:4"/>all the Vicious and Imperti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent <hi>Humours</hi> of the Age, as none are more <hi>Common,</hi> so none are more <hi>Equally</hi> Lamentable, Dangerous and Rediculous, than Aspersing things Venerable and Sacred, and speaking Evil of Illustrious Persons; and yet that is now Improved to such a <hi>Wicked</hi> Height, that he is account<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the <hi>Witiest</hi> Man, and <hi>Stanchest</hi> Member of his Party, that dares ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lumniate <hi>Loudest;</hi> or else has the Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culiar <hi>knack</hi> in wounding Authority, with <hi>Sly, Oblique</hi> and <hi>Ominous</hi> Sug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gestions; that can <hi>Stab,</hi> and look another way, as if they were wholly <hi>Innocent,</hi> and unconcern'd in the Mischiefs, that are <hi>only</hi> of their own contriving.</p>
            <p>Now were these mean and scanda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lous <hi>Practices,</hi> to be found only a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong a <hi>few,</hi> from whose weak and crazy Heads better Morals could not be <hi>expected,</hi> like a slight <hi>scratch</hi> in the Body, it might be cured by ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>glecting and contemning it; but since the Disease is grown Epidemical, and has intruded into <hi>Topping</hi> Societies, 'tis time to put a stop to the Gan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>green, before the whole Body of the People are <hi>Infected,</hi> and grow sick of their <hi>Prosperity.</hi> Next our Duty towards God, it greatly concerns our <hi>Peace</hi> and <hi>Happiness,</hi> to <hi>Uphold</hi> our Loyalty to God's Anointed, and our <hi>Obedience</hi> to his Government; for our Peace and Safety being wrapt up in the <hi>Welfare</hi> of the King, and the Prosperity of his Laws, 'tis our Wisdom and Interest to be <hi>True</hi> to both, and bear a just Abhorrence of all Seditious <hi>Members</hi> in the Kingdom, who would weaken the <hi>Head,</hi> to fortify the <hi>Body,</hi> and would perswade us, that to <hi>Traduce</hi> and <hi>Expose</hi> his Majesty, is the way to make <hi>his</hi> Reign, and <hi>our</hi> Lives happy; and that the Diminution of his Regal Power and Prerogatives, is the way to <hi>support</hi> his Grandeur, and make Three Kingdoms <hi>Happy.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>These are the abominable fallacies, which <hi>some</hi> Seditious <hi>Members</hi> of our Body Politick, are putting up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Fickle and Injudicious <hi>Popu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lace,</hi> with design to abase the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>narch's <hi>Legal</hi> Power, and <hi>Lodge</hi> it in themselves; and therefore 'tis eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry honest Man's <hi>concern</hi> to oppose these wicked Antimonarchial Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciples and Practices, and to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vince Men by the <hi>Truth</hi> and <hi>Reason</hi> of the thing, that the way to be happy our <hi>selves,</hi> is first to make the King so; and that to obey him <hi>Humbly,</hi> to Honour him <hi>Conscienti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ously,</hi> and to Love him <hi>Affectionately</hi> and <hi>Heartily,</hi> is both our Duty and Advantage; whereas to cast off that Reverence that he has a <hi>Just</hi> Right to, to <hi>Misconstrue</hi> his Actions, to <hi>Traduce</hi> his Counsels, to <hi>suspect</hi> his Integrity, and if it were possible to render him <hi>Cheap</hi> and Insignificant, which is the <hi>Course</hi> that is now ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king by our <hi>Pseudo Patriots,</hi> is to tear our Peace, our Government, and <hi>All</hi> to pieces, without the help of a Forreign Enemy.</p>
            <p>Sure <hi>England</hi> is the <hi>Unhappiest</hi> Island in the World, that can ne're be Prosperous and Peaceable, Fortu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:44100:4"/>and Loyal, Safe and Contented at the same time. For no sooner are we on the Borders of a <hi>happy</hi> Settle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, but Ill <hi>Accidents</hi> or Malicious <hi>Inventions,</hi> intervene to Cross and Disturb it. No sooner are we in possession of a <hi>long</hi> desired Peace, but some Seditious Chymaera's, Nick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nam'd <hi>the Publick Good,</hi> or some cun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ningly staged Fears and Jealousies, Suspicions and <hi>feigned</hi> Dangers, (which if duly Examin'd, are no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing but the results of a Spirit of Contradiction, and disobedience to Monarchial Authority) throws us into such <hi>violent</hi> Concussions and preternatural <hi>Heart-burnings,</hi> that the Nation, like a Distracted Body, is laying Hands upon it self, and contributing more to its Ruine, by its own Heats and Divisions, than the Swords of our Enemies could effect.</p>
            <p>Detestable Jealousy and Suspici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on! How <hi>Dismal</hi> are thy Products? How <hi>Destructive</hi> to Christian Chari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty? How <hi>Pernicious</hi> to Humane So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cieties? That no Bond is so strong, no Tye so sacred, no Deliverance so obliging, but this deluding <hi>Inchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tress</hi> is able to dissolve them.</p>
            <p>What shall we say? Sure some strange <hi>Fatality,</hi> some unusual, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>heard of <hi>Giddiness,</hi> has seiz'd and Infatuated some <hi>Members</hi> of the Kingdom, that they should take Pleasure in Affronting their <hi>King and Deliverer,</hi> and out of an Innate A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>version to Monarchy, refuse to do themselves and their Country <hi>Right,</hi> for no other Reason, but because they thought the King desir'd it. Is not this to Retort his signal Favours with <hi>Indignities,</hi> to Requite his Love with Jealousies, and to sting him with our <hi>Tongues,</hi> while he is <hi>warm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> us in his <hi>Bosom?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Did he not deliver us from Tyra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny and Oppression? Has he not Fought our Battles, and procur'd us Peace and Plenty? These Favours one would think, had been enough to oblige a People of <hi>any</hi> Ingenuity, and for ever <hi>Indear'd</hi> a Prince to us, who snatch'd us from the brink of Ruine, and with the Hazard of his own Life, preserv'd <hi>Ours,</hi> and the Kingdom.</p>
            <p>Sure tho' we are unable to Requite him, we ought not to <hi>Injure</hi> him in his Honour, by <hi>base</hi> Surmises, and <hi>Unwarrantable</hi> Suspicions, and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stead of Treating him with the <hi>high<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>est</hi> Epithets of Royalty, scarce afford him the Civil usage of a <hi>Gentleman;</hi> certainly this is Ingratitude in the Abstract, and wants a Name <hi>bad</hi> e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nough to signify its baseness; and that it may yet appear more Black, and Fright the Seditious from <hi>Repea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting</hi> their Crimes, by shewing them a Monster of their own begetting; let us look a little backward, and trace it to its Original.</p>
            <p>Our late <hi>Inability</hi> to Extricate our selves, and our Laws, from a Threatn'd Slavery, and Vassalage to a <hi>Homebred</hi> and <hi>Forreign</hi> Tyranny; and to defend our Liberties and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perties, from the Insults and Depre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dations of our <hi>own</hi> Countrymen and Strangers, made it absolutely neces<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sary for us, to Resign our Power in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:44100:5"/>the Hands of the Prince of <hi>Orange, now our gracious King;</hi> who wrought such a <hi>Deliverance</hi> for the Nation, as ought <hi>never</hi> to be forgotten, and can <hi>never</hi> be sufficiently Requited; if we consider both the <hi>Matter</hi> which was Great, and the <hi>Mannner</hi> which was kind, and both Extraordinary, and which will be mention'd with <hi>Honour</hi> by Men of <hi>Sence,</hi> so long as the <hi>Protestant</hi> Name shall be remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bred.</p>
            <p>His Majesty came not as the An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tient <hi>Romans</hi> and <hi>Saxons,</hi> to <hi>Conquer</hi> and lead in <hi>Triumph</hi> after him, our Religion and Laws, our Lives and Liberties; but to <hi>Defend, Preserve, and Secure us in them all.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>For this end <hi>alone</hi> he undertook that Dangerous and Chargeable Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pedition, which has prov'd as much to <hi>our</hi> Advantage, as it will be to His Majesty's <hi>lasting</hi> Reputation.</p>
            <p>What he has done, Argues that he was moved by a Higher Principle than any this World can afford; in over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>looking his <hi>own</hi> ease and Securiry, when the <hi>Publik</hi> Good, and the <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerns</hi> of Christianity, call'd for his Seasonable Assistance. And</p>
            <p>Here I could easily make a <hi>Pane<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gyric</hi> upon his vertues, and equal him to the most famous <hi>Graecian</hi> and <hi>Roman</hi> Generals; but I need not set forth <hi>his</hi> Praises, which do so loud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly speak for themselves. Nor draw any tedious Parallels betwixt His <hi>Majesty,</hi> and the Celebrated <hi>Hero</hi>'s of former Ages, since I am herein prevented, by all who have read the <gap reason="illegible: page cropped" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> and are Ocular <hi>Witnesses</hi> of what his Prince<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Goodness, with so much Cou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage, Mildness, and Prudence, hath done in this; for things succeeded so well under his <hi>Conduct,</hi> that we all submitted our selves to his <hi>Wise</hi> Direction, and put our selves un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der his Gracious <hi>Protection,</hi> as the <hi>Tutelar Genius</hi> of the Nation: And the <hi>Effects</hi> of his Enterprize were so strange, so Wonderful, and Surpri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zing, that had we not <hi>seen,</hi> we should scarce have <hi>believed</hi> them, which makes the wonder greater, that we should so easily forget them.</p>
            <p>As soon as His Majesty Landed, with what <hi>Joy,</hi> and universal good <hi>wishes</hi> was the News received? How forward were all sorts af People to <hi>Declare</hi> for his Highness; How <hi>willing</hi> were they to lend him a <hi>help<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> hand, for accomplishing his great Work? How did we all generally concur, and unanimously agree, to <hi>forget</hi> our obligation to the late King, and assist his present <hi>Majesty,</hi> rather than <hi>James</hi> the Second, against our selves and his own Interest?</p>
            <p>Nay, the Army it self, that now some <hi>Scurrilous and Trifling Pens have loaded with Opprobrious Names, and Stigmatiz'd with base and Ungenerous Reflections; for doing the best piece of Service that e're was done for</hi> England; went over to him, choosing rather to lye under the imputation of Cow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ardize, and Disloyalty (which yet <hi>True</hi> English Men had rather <hi>dye</hi> than really <hi>deserve</hi>) than to be <hi>Instrumental</hi> in Enslaving their <hi>Native</hi> Country, and bringing it <hi>again</hi> under the Yoke</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:44100:5"/>
            <p> In short, all Orders of Men, <hi>Ec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clesiastick, Civil,</hi> and <hi>Military,</hi> had their Eyes <hi>fix'd</hi> upon his present Majesty, as their great Deliverer, were <hi>resolv'd</hi> to espouse his Cause, and accordingly when the late King had withdrawn himself. First, put the Regal Administration into his Hands, and soon after by a Univer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sal Consent, set the Imperial Diadem upon his Head. <hi>Where may it flourish for many many Years.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now, who that ever heard the <hi>doleful</hi> Sighs, and Lamentations of <hi>English Protestants,</hi> when their Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion was in danger of being <hi>lost,</hi> and Popery, Idolatry, and Superstition, was setting up as the <hi>National</hi> mode of Worship could ever imagine, that the <hi>English</hi> could so <hi>soon,</hi> and so un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gratefully, forget the benefit of <hi>re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>storing</hi> their Religion, or make any <hi>Undecent</hi> returns to King <hi>William,</hi> that accomplish'd it.</p>
            <p>Who that ever knew, how in the late Reign our <hi>Laws</hi> were suspended, our <hi>Properties</hi> Seized, our Rights and Liberties <hi>Invaded,</hi> and Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stants insulted by furious Papists, could ever think to <hi>see the day,</hi> that any <hi>English</hi> Protestant should requite Good with Evil, and indust<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riously <hi>Slaunder</hi> the Footsteps of the Lords <hi>Anointed,</hi> that <hi>heal'd</hi> all our Breaches, and restored us to <hi>Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Who that has ever heard, or read, the humble Remonstrance, and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quest, of a <hi>Considerable</hi> part of the <hi>English</hi> Clergy, Nobility, Gentry, and Commons, to King <hi>William,</hi> (when in <hi>Holland</hi>) <hi>to come over and help them:</hi> The promises they made of standing by him with their Lives and Fortunes, and how <hi>chearfully</hi> that great Prince <hi>undertook,</hi> and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>most miraculously <hi>accomplish'd</hi> our Deliverance, could believe that the <hi>same</hi> Prince, should from the same <hi>people</hi> receive a less Dutiful and Glorious Return, than the Noble Enterprize deserved.</p>
            <p>Who, that has ever heard, how unanimously, and freely, the <hi>Repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sentatives</hi> of the Nation in the <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vention</hi> at <hi>Westminster,</hi> offer'd his <hi>Highness</hi> and his <hi>Princess</hi> the Crown? How they <hi>rejoic'd</hi> at their Accep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance of it, and with what <hi>extraor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinary</hi> Solemnity and Satisfaction they were Proclaim'd and Crown'd <hi>King and Queen of</hi> England, could ever think of seeing any thing that should look like a <hi>Diminution</hi> of his Royal Authority, or <hi>Suspect</hi> his Kindness and good Intentions to a Nation, that he had <hi>Obliged</hi> beyond Expression?</p>
            <p>Who could think, that after Acts of <hi>Settlement, Recognition</hi> of the King's <hi>Right, Association</hi> for his <hi>Safety,</hi> and setling a Fund for the War, and a Maintenance of his Royalty, that a <hi>sullen, froward and seditious Sort of People should rise up among us,</hi> of all Qualities, but of no Religion, or moral Prudence, to beget a misun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derstanding betwixt this <hi>glorious King,</hi> and these <hi>Loyal People,</hi> whose mutual Concord and Agreement is the <hi>safety</hi> of the Kingdom, and the <hi>Terror</hi> of its Enemies.</p>
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:44100:6"/>
            <p> However; a few such there were, even in that very Parliament, that had given such ample Demonstrati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons of their Love and Loyalty. For the Nation having then a War up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on its hands, (for the maintenance of our new Settlement) with a Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent Monarch that protected the Person, and espous'd the Quarrel of the late Abdicated King; and that great <hi>Supplies</hi> were <hi>absolutely</hi> neces<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sary, to enable his Majesty to su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stain the Force of a Kingdom, which by their own <hi>Wise</hi> Administration, and the <hi>Supineness</hi> of <hi>England</hi> in the late Inglorious Reigns, was now grown so <hi>Potent,</hi> that it required a longer Sword to <hi>Resist,</hi> than hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore to <hi>Conquer</hi> it, and in which his Majesty (without flattery) has ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quir'd more Honour, by <hi>checking</hi> and <hi>controwling</hi> the Power of <hi>France,</hi> than any of his great <hi>Predecessors</hi> did by subduing it; the Parliaments were oblig'd to lay great Taxes up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the People, and the Nation be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing not insensible of the Burden, the Malecontented <hi>Jacobites</hi> who were always more cunning in embroiling our Affairs, than in advancing their own, took the advantage of it, and in all Companies declared, that the Government must of <hi>necessity</hi> sink un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der its own <hi>Weight,</hi> and that our <hi>Heavy Taxes</hi> by reducing us to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tream <hi>Poverty,</hi> would inevitably prove our Destruction: And never ceas'd declaiming on this <hi>popular</hi> Subject, and galling the People in their <hi>Tender</hi> part; in hopes to make 'em weary of a Government, which was represented so <hi>burthensom,</hi> and to perswade them rather to let in the <hi>Deluge,</hi> than be at the Expence of <hi>maintaining</hi> the Banks.</p>
            <p>Besides this <hi>Party</hi> that were for King <hi>James,</hi> there were others, <hi>that were for no King at all,</hi> a sort of <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>publicans</hi> of the old Stamp, that are for <hi>subverting</hi> Monarchy it self, to set up an Idol they know not what in the Room on't; and care not what becomes of <hi>King,</hi> and <hi>Parliament,</hi> and <hi>Kingdom</hi> too, so they can grati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fy their own Pride and Peevishness, and advance the <hi>Dagon</hi> of a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-Wealth; which is so inconsi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stent with the Humor, Nature, In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terest and Constitution of the <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lish</hi> People and Government, that they might as well attempt to stem the Tide, or reconcile disagreeing Elements, as think either to court or force them to submit to such a Form; yet however unlikely it was to expect the Peoples compliance, they use their utmost endeavour to promote it, and to this end Mr. <hi>Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rington's Common-Wealth of Oceana,</hi> and all Mr. <hi>Milton</hi>'s Antimonarchi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal Treatises, and that too, which justifies the <hi>Murder</hi> of <hi>Charles</hi> the First, and many Discourses of other Authors, as <hi>Ludlow</hi>'s Letters, and Mr. <hi>Sidney</hi>'s Discourse of Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, all on the same Subject, and tending to promote the Design of <hi>Lessening</hi> and <hi>Reproaching</hi> Monarchy, are Reprinted, which, in their Ends and Designs, as well as their Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thors, are no less Enemies to the Government, their King and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:44100:6"/>than the former, and assist in carrying on Discontents and Divisi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons among us, being such an <hi>odd</hi> sort of Men, and so <hi>averse</hi> to all Kings, that if God should send them one from Heaven, they'd never like him two days together; Nay, if they were in <hi>Heaven</hi> themselves, 'tis to be fear'd they'd be turn'd out again, for Attempting against the Monar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chical Power of God Almighty. These, I say, are some of the <hi>Trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blers</hi> of our <hi>Israel,</hi> and are no less busy in <hi>Traducing</hi> the King, than the <hi>Rankest Jacobites</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> and greedily swallow down any <hi>Defa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation</hi> upon the Court, to disgorge it with a greater mixture of Malice and Slaunder at their next Repub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lican Association. And tho' they are both in extreams, and as oppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>site to the <hi>Jacobites</hi> in their Princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples, as they are to Peace and Loy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty; yet they both agree in <hi>Opi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion</hi> and <hi>Practice</hi> against King <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam,</hi> and his Government, and take the <hi>same</hi> Methods of Lying and Slaundering, and raising Fears and Jealousies to <hi>weaken</hi> and destroy it.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Jacobites</hi> said we should ne're have <hi>Peace</hi> till <hi>James the Second</hi> was Restor'd; and the <hi>Republicans</hi> said we should ne're be able to cope with our Enemies, but must sink under them, if we did not put our selves under the Regiment of a Common-Wealth, and Crown our Sov. L. the People. These contradictory Noti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons were both supported by their <hi>Pamphleteers</hi> without Doors, and their crafty and dissembling <hi>Ambo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dexters</hi> Within, who, by Asserting the War was like to be <hi>Eternal,</hi> and the Nation's Ruin irretrivable, were <hi>Tearing</hi> the Bowels of our Common Mother, and plunging us into <hi>new</hi> Confusins, by the <hi>united</hi> endeavours of those that were for a popish Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitrary King, and those that were for <hi>no King at all.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But the never to be forgotten <hi>goodness</hi> of God, and the great <hi>Wis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom,</hi> Invincible <hi>Courage,</hi> and <hi>inflexi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble</hi> Resolution of his Majesty, ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving to the great <hi>Mortification</hi> of the Enemies of the King and Kingdom. The intire <hi>Satisfaction</hi> of the true Friends of both, and the <hi>Admiration</hi> of all Men; concluded the War with <hi>France,</hi> and brought home an <hi>Hon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ourable Peace,</hi> it confuted all their <hi>Ominous</hi> predictions, silenc'd their <hi>Clamours,</hi> shamed their <hi>Intrigues,</hi> and confounded all the pretended dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers, rais'd by our Enemies. And now one would think, we had no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing to do, but to return our <hi>due</hi> thanks to God and the King, make our Gratitude and Obedience, as <hi>Conspicuous</hi> as the benefit was <hi>Extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ordinary;</hi> to pay our <hi>Debts,</hi> Reward our <hi>Friends,</hi> forgive our <hi>Enemies,</hi> and under our own Vines and Fig-Trees, solace our selves in a hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>py Peace, and live in Unity and A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mity, and in Peace and Concord a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong our selves.</p>
            <p>These were the things most desi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable, best becoming Professors of Christianity, sutable to our Obliga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, and ought to have been the Endeavours of all in their several
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:44100:7"/>Stations. But alass, to shew <hi>there is nothing compleatly happy on this side Heaven,</hi> How have we frustrated the Designs of God Almighty, whose Goodness and long Suffering should have led us to Repentance, by con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinuing in our Impieties? How <hi>Ill</hi> and <hi>Ungratefully</hi> have we treated his <hi>Majesty,</hi> who as the Royal Instru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in the Hand of God, has pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cur'd us this, and many other ine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stimable Blessings? And how have we injur'd the whole Community, by dividing into <hi>Parties</hi> and <hi>Fact<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ions,</hi> and worrying one another by Intestine Seditions? For,</p>
            <p>No sooner was there a Dissoluti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the former Parliament, and a fresh one convened, but <hi>New</hi> Mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>murers, under the Names of <hi>Old Friends,</hi> (though in truth but a com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pound of the other Two) started up amongst us to trouble our Affairs; who, though great Asserters of the late Revolution, seem inclinable e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nough to a <hi>second,</hi> if their private Sentiments may be collected from their publick Discourses: For from I know not what private Disgusts, and and personal Quarrels and Disa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointments, they are grown Sowr and uneasie; and to express their Resentments; in all Conversation indeavour to bring our <hi>Administra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion</hi> into contempt: To clog the Wheels of the Government that it move slowly, or not at all; and, in short, are against all things which our known and open Enemies are a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst, and for all things which they are for and <gap reason="illegible: page cropped" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the consequences be as mischievous as they will, they think the more the better; and by these and other Clandestine Popular Arts, <hi>Recommend themselves to their Country as great Patriots,</hi> for no other reason but that they would <hi>Starve,</hi> or bind up the hands of the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, that it should not be able to support and defend it self. The pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceedings against these men, whither in their own <hi>Houses</hi> or at <hi>Clubbs,</hi> are of all others the most absur'd and unaccountable, and the Opposition they make against the Government, seems to be the effect of some strange Infatuation. For tho' it should be allowed, as 'tis a standing Maxim a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong them that the Character of a <hi>Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>triot,</hi> without distinction of <hi>Times</hi> or <hi>Persons,</hi> is to be <hi>always,</hi> and in all <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ses</hi> whatsoever, against the <hi>Court;</hi> yet they cannot be unsensible, that the Face of Affairs is so alter'd by the late happy <hi>Revolution,</hi> that the Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rest of their <hi>Country</hi> is the same with that of the <hi>Court.</hi> However, tho' this was a Government of their own <hi>Choosing, Approving</hi> and <hi>Settling,</hi> which methinks should weigh much with all considering Men, that would not be thought guilty of <hi>Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vity, Novelty and Inconstancy;</hi> yet the Witchcarft of <hi>Parity, Envy</hi> and <hi>Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bition</hi> gives them such a satisfaction in <hi>Crossing</hi> the King, <hi>Thwarting</hi> the <hi>Court,</hi> and by those <hi>Arts</hi> rendring themselves Popular, that 'tis the Bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>siness of their Lives to make the King and his Ministers <hi>Uneasy,</hi> and, if 'twere to be done, <hi>Despicable</hi> in the eyes of the People. Now</p>
            <pb n="9" facs="tcp:44100:7"/>
            <p> Were these Mischiefs done by the open and <hi>profest</hi> Enemies of the King and Government, the Crime would be more tolerable: or were they hatch'd by the <hi>little</hi> Animals that frequent Seditious Coffee-Houses, it would be more pardonable, because their Tongues are no <hi>slander;</hi> but to see and hear it done by our <hi>pretended Friends,</hi> Men of <hi>Quality</hi> and <hi>Figure,</hi> that are in Eminent Posts in the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, that have a Hand in Publick Affairs, is able to chill and stagger every Sense about one! and what can these scandalous Practices be ascrib'd to, but a deep dy'd Dissimu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation and Hypocrisy; when we see Men Court and Cringe at <hi>Kensington,</hi> and rail at <hi>Westminster;</hi> Hug and Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brace a Minister in the <hi>Painted Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber,</hi> and cut his Throat in the <hi>Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel;</hi> give a Courtier the smoothest Words to his Face, and hang him behind his Back. What can one think, but that they were <hi>Tainted</hi> in their <hi>Original,</hi> and are so in Love with <hi>Anarchy,</hi> that they hate the King, and all that belong to him; and let them pretend what they please, from <hi>this</hi> Principle you can never <hi>Court</hi> nor <hi>Drive</hi> them, for the <hi>Moor</hi> was born <hi>black,</hi> and will con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue so, in <hi>despite</hi> of all the Sope i'th'Kingdom. The Snakes will be <hi>Hissing</hi> and threatning, and if you should cram them with all they can wish, or you can give, they will ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver lose their Natures; and of these there are two sorts, and both worth the Knowing, that you may avoid them.</p>
            <p>First, the loud and open <hi>Talkers;</hi> and secondly, the private seditious <hi>Whisperers.</hi> The first need no parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular Description, for the <hi>Noise</hi> they make, and the <hi>Hazard</hi> they run of forfeiting their <hi>Understandings,</hi> to gratifie their Ill Nature, and <hi>humour</hi> their Faction, is the best Denomina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of them. These, though al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways <hi>Declaiming</hi> against the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, do <hi>less</hi> harm than the other; for all their Invectives against the <hi>King</hi> and <hi>Court,</hi> being usually car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried as far above <hi>Truth,</hi> as beyond the Bounds of <hi>Decency,</hi> they are not like to succeed in their <hi>Designs;</hi> un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>less when they assume a power of <hi>Talking</hi> away their King's <hi>Right,</hi> they could take away the Peoples <hi>Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son</hi> also; which can never be done by Men whose Understandings are warp'd with their Interests, and are not <hi>Historians</hi> of publick Actions, but <hi>Lawyers</hi> of a <hi>Party:</hi> For ground<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing all they say upon <hi>Idle Tales, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ports,</hi> and <hi>Hearsays,</hi> they prove no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing but their want of <hi>Breeding,</hi> and <hi>better</hi> Arguments, and their <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lumnies</hi> when driven home, will re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coil upon their own Heads: For they that charge others with Crimes they cannot <hi>justifie,</hi> Indite and Convict themselves of <hi>Falsity.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The <hi>Private Whisperers</hi> are com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly Men of a superior Quality, such as are ashamed to own their Practices openly, and therefore like Gun-powder in a Vault, do incom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parably the more Mischies for being stifled. For though they take <hi>Plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sure</hi> to be always finding <hi>Fault,</hi> ever
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:44100:8"/>
               <hi>Complaining</hi> and <hi>Murmering,</hi> and <hi>Cen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>suring</hi> the <hi>wisest</hi> Councils, and the <hi>uprightest</hi> Conduct; yet they still sculk <hi>behind</hi> the Curtain, and look as <hi>Demure</hi> and <hi>Harmless,</hi> as if they had no <hi>conceal'd</hi> Sting, nor no <hi>Gaul</hi> was mix'd in their Creation, when they are the greatest Enemies to the King and Government in the World. For though they do not speak <hi>di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectly,</hi> and in terms against his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesty; yet they vent such base Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flections, and unmannerly Insinuati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons against him, under <hi>double</hi> and <hi>Abiguous</hi> Meanings, as <hi>poyson</hi> the Ears of their Admirers, and prepare their Tongues to use a greater Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty 'Tis from such pernicious <hi>Presidents</hi> of scandalous <hi>Babling</hi> and Idle <hi>Whispering</hi> against Authority, that the <hi>Leudness</hi> of the Tongue be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comes so epidemical in the Nation, and that the common People, first corrupted by <hi>Ill</hi> Principles, and then <hi>Influenc'd</hi> by the Example of Facti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous <hi>Great Ones,</hi> are grown to such <hi>Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cesses</hi> in their <hi>Pragmatical</hi> censuring the Actions of their <hi>Superiors,</hi> as is unsufferable to the Loyal and Sober part of Mankind; Dangerous to the State, and ple<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ing to none but <hi>Sedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tious Incendiaries,</hi> who play the <hi>Body</hi> against the <hi>Head,</hi> with design to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroy the whole.</p>
            <p>What a strange Liberty is taken in this licentious Age, when every private Person, that thinks he has half a dram of Brains about him, shall Arraign the Actions of their Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>periors. What is this, but blasting the choisest Flowers of the <hi>Crown,</hi> and shrinking the <hi>Imperial</hi> Dignity of our English <hi>Monarch,</hi> into a <hi>Doge</hi> of <hi>Venice?</hi> For he is but a <hi>Titular</hi> and no <hi>Real</hi> King, whose Sovereign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, and Prerogative Royal, is liable to the <hi>Popular</hi> Scannings and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fractions of every <hi>Proud</hi> and <hi>Peevish</hi> Subject. There is no Tyranny to be compar'd to the Tyranny of a Sedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tious <hi>Multitude,</hi> and the condition of our <hi>English</hi> Kings are very little mended by those, that free them from the <hi>Pope</hi>'s Supremacy <hi>in ordine ad bonum spirituale,</hi> and subject them to the <hi>People, in ordine ad bonum pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licum:</hi> For if General Assemblies for making Laws have but the power of <hi>Advising</hi> the King, 'tis the highest <hi>Insolence</hi> in private Persons, to cen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sure and misrepresent him. Are the Kings Prerogatives and Sovereignty the only Rights that may be <hi>Inva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded,</hi> and scandalously <hi>toss'd</hi> from Mouth to Mouth, as if the King that owns them were not <hi>Sacred,</hi> and exempted from such impertinent Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courses? Sure the World is turn'd <hi>Topsy Turvy,</hi> and Mens Understand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing grow <hi>Downward,</hi> or they could never think the <hi>Multitude</hi> are invested with the highest price of <hi>Regality,</hi> viz. <hi>Judging of the Publick Good, and Controwling all;</hi> whose Incapacity, Levity, and Ignorance, renders 'em unfit for any thing of this Nature. Therefore, if any such are found, that by <hi>Usurping</hi> upon the King's So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vereignty, would plead for such a <hi>Priviledge</hi> of the Subject, the <hi>Cock<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>atrice</hi> ought to be crush'd in the Fgg, their Tongues should be tyed
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:44100:8"/>as well as their Hands; nay, the boyling of their Thoughts when they rise so high should be scumm'd, and suppress'd, or all will run into the Fire of Contention.</p>
            <p>Though after all, I cannot be so Injurious to the generality of his Majesty's <hi>People,</hi> as to think they aim at any thing above the Sphere of <hi>Dutiful Subjects;</hi> for their <hi>Zeal</hi> and forwardness to venture their Lives in his Majesty's <hi>Service,</hi> is a manifest contradiction of such a Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lumny, and a convincing Evidence of their constant Loyalty and Fide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity; and my only Design in expo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing the Principle was to shew, that <hi>Kinging</hi> the <hi>Multitude,</hi> is only a <hi>Trick</hi> to weaken the <hi>Monarchy,</hi> and is im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy'd as a Blind, (by some that in the Course of Affairs, are come to have a share in great Actions) to a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>muse the Nation with this Popular, and <hi>Taking</hi> Theme, while they are laying a Foundation for their own Arbitrary Ends, and uncontrowl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able Authority.</p>
            <p>Having therefore acquainted my Reader, that the Government had Three sorts of Enemies, <hi>Jacobites, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>publicans,</hi> and <hi>Discontended Mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>murers,</hi> which under the mask of <hi>Friendship</hi> were great Underminers of the Government, 'tis now my bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>siness to shew, <hi>that according to an old laid Scheme of the Jacobites to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroy the Government,</hi> to the Three factions already Named, are added another set of Enemies, more <hi>danger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous</hi> than all the rest to effect it, which to distinguish from the former, I call <hi>The Mixture, New Converts, or Sediti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Interpositors,</hi> whose designs having been the Work of great Thoughts, and long time. And now, as the <hi>last</hi> Game is beginning to be plaid among us.</p>
            <p>I know it will displease the <hi>Repub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licans,</hi> to be coupled with the <hi>Jacc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bites;</hi> our Male-contented Murmur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing pretended Friends, to be join'd with the other Two; and our New Converts to be Link'd with them all; however, in the cause of my <hi>King</hi> and <hi>Country,</hi> that are Harras'd and sawne by this unhappy <hi>Mixture</hi> of various Interests, combin'd against them, which like Beasts of different Species, and Sexes, shut up together, forget their Natural Emnity, to satisfy their common Lusts, and care not what kind of <hi>Monsters</hi> are produced be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>twixt them, so their Brutal appe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties are but gratified. I shall not value what they can say, or do, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst me; for as 'tis a Symptom of an ill cause, when it can't bear <hi>Examin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> and that none are so much concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned at Reflections, as those that cause them, so an Honest design of indea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vouring the <hi>Peace</hi> of the Nation, as it don't deferve, so it will not stand in fear of any Mens <hi>Displeasure;</hi> and therefore I shall proceed to shew, that the Farce now Acting, is but an Inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lude Revived. That the Actors un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der what <hi>disguise</hi> or <hi>Dress</hi> soever they appear, are but <hi>Tooles</hi> in the hands of the <hi>Jacobites,</hi> and while they <hi>Saty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rize</hi> the <hi>Monarchy</hi> and publick <hi>Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nagement,</hi> are but <hi>compounding</hi> with the Court at <hi>St. Germans,</hi> and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>triving,
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:44100:9"/>and Advancing the designs of the Frustrated Faction.</p>
            <p>'Twas a smart reply of a <hi>Great Man,</hi> when acquainted with the Danger that might arise from the great number of Men, crowded into both Houses, that were in the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terest of King <hi>James,</hi> he said, <hi>There was equal danger from his false Friends, and from them that were for no King at all.</hi> And tho' this single obser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation has <hi>Weight</hi> enough in it, to preponderate any objection that can be made against it, I hope it will not be taken <hi>Ill,</hi> to prove by matter of Fact, that the Supposition of there being such a Conjunction, was not groundless, and consequently that the Reflection was a Wise and pru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent <hi>Reprehension,</hi> of confining the <hi>Whole</hi> danger to a <hi>Single</hi> faction, when there were apparent Instances, that Others were in the same <hi>Unnatural</hi> Confederacy.</p>
            <p>Those Gentlemen that serv'd his Majesty in the Counsells and Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bals of his Enemies know, and are able to prove, that the Jacobites had certain standing Rules, and Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thods, to govern themselves by in all their attempts against his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sty's Government, which were early communicated to his Ministers, and daily observation has shew'd, as they have been bafled in <hi>any One,</hi> the <hi>Next</hi> has been taken up with equal heat and Vigour as the former; and now <hi>Three</hi> of their four <hi>Projects</hi> encoun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tring continued <hi>Disappointments;</hi> the last, which gives us so much trouble, and if not prevented will give us <hi>More,</hi> is now upon the <hi>Stage,</hi> and great are the expectations of our E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nemies from it.</p>
            <p>The Projects prescrib'd to the Jacobites, for the <hi>Restoration</hi> of their old Masters, were couched under these four heads.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>First,</hi> To join with the <hi>Republicans,</hi> and all the <hi>Malcontented</hi> under every Denomination. This failing, then</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Secondly,</hi> To <hi>Strengthen</hi> their Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, by calling in a Forreign Power; and if that was unsuccessful. Then</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Thirdly,</hi> To do the Work at <hi>Once,</hi> by <hi>Assassinating</hi> his Majesties Royal <hi>Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son,</hi> and in him the whole Kingdom.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Fourthly,</hi> If all the former me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thods were rendred ineffectual, then <hi>they should all come into the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, take the Oaths, and set up for new Converts.</hi> And this I call <hi>The Mistery of Iniquity, that is now in working.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Two first of these projects for the <hi>Destruction</hi> of the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, were a while kept with great <hi>Secresy,</hi> and practiced with no less caution and fears of <hi>Discovery;</hi> but as Trees when they have shot their Roots deep in the Earth, and have spread their Branches wide in the Air, every one may confidently affirm, they were of no very late Planting; So by a <hi>Wonderful Turn of Providence,</hi> the Confederacy be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the Seditious of all Names, and Factions with the Jacobites, was fully discover'd. <hi>Lawton, Ferguson,</hi> and <hi>Grosby,</hi> proper Tooles for such a Work, were apprehended; and the <hi>Lord Preston</hi>'s Plot, wherein the <hi>Ori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginal</hi> Papers, and Letters of the <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spirators</hi>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:44100:9"/>declare there was a <hi>Combi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation</hi> to subvert the Government, to <hi>Depose,</hi> if not <hi>Murder,</hi> the King and Queen, say, That this Villany was Methodically agreed, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluded, at a Select and for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mal Conference<note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>Mr.</hi> Ashtons <hi>Tryal.</hi>
               </note>
               <hi>between Divers Lords and Gentlemen both Whiggs and Tories.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The next contrivance of the <hi>Jaco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bites,</hi> was the profess'd <hi>Murder</hi> of the <hi>King,</hi> and the <hi>Invasion</hi> of the Kingdom; but Heaven detected the <hi>Conspiracy,</hi> and the Barbarity of the Action, has so branded the whole Party, with the Scorn, Infamy and Hatred of all <hi>English</hi>-Men, that they being now asham'd to shew their Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces as <hi>Jacobites,</hi> take Sanctuary in their <hi>last Project,</hi> which I told you was, <hi>To submit to the Government, to take the Oaths of Fidelity, and set up for Converts, that under shew of Friendship and Sincerity, they might gain an opportuniy to Herd with other seditious Persons, and do more Mis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chief by their seeming complyance, than they were able to effect by their pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fess'd and open Enmity.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And here I beg not to be miscon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strued, as if I grudg'd at any Man's <hi>Conversion</hi> to his Duty, or thought it an Injury to the State to have the Love and Service of the whole Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munity: For 'tis what I heartily wish, and for some Years have em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy'd my Pen for; but when I see Men the same in <hi>Principle</hi> and <hi>Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctice,</hi> since they became <hi>Williamites,</hi> as they were when <hi>distinguish'd</hi> from good Subjects, by the Name of <hi>Ja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cobites;</hi> you will pardon me for suspecting the sincerity of their Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>version, till they give o're the Trade of <hi>perverting their Brethren, and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibite</hi> more signal Evidences of their Virtue and Loyalty, then yet they have done since they came among us.</p>
            <p>The Sacred Oracles tell us, <hi>that by their Works we may know Men,</hi> and then what can we think, when we see the whole <hi>Gang</hi> of Enemies Haunt the Court, for no other end but to Redicule and abuse it! Set up for <hi>Patriots,</hi> by sowing the Seeds of Sedition! Get themselves to be E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected <hi>Members,</hi> that they may have the privilege of affronting their So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vereign, <hi>saying,</hi> that within Doors, that a modest Man durst not <hi>Think</hi> without! Contend for a <hi>Popular</hi> Omnipotency, and liberty to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroy all our Franchises; and <hi>Lessen</hi> the Kings Power to give more than is due to their <hi>Own!</hi> What (I say) can we think of these Proceedings, but that their coming among us, is like Water into a Ship, not to <hi>Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cour,</hi> but to <hi>Sink</hi> us; for such things have been acted in days of Yore, and what has been done may be done again, if an Almighty Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence does not prevent it.</p>
            <p>That this is the Design to be drea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded, appears as well by the great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness of their Numbers, as the na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture of their Actions; for since the Year when this Commerce began, we have had a greater <hi>Addition</hi> to our Malecontents, than from the <hi>be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginning</hi> of the Revolution to that un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>happy
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:44100:10"/>Junction. And the Trade of supplying every vacancy in the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, with Persons of the same Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racter, Increasing rather than abate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, I wish surcharging the Factory, does not Bankrupt the Nation. That the confluence of our new Sediti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Interpositers, does not infect us with our <hi>Old</hi> Plagues, and that these Upstart <hi>Pseudo Patriots,</hi> being added to the Number of the Old <hi>Jacobites, Republicans</hi> and <hi>Murmerers</hi> we had before, it had not been better for us, rather to have had their <hi>Room</hi> than their <hi>Company.</hi> For I fear if a Man might look into some Houses, he would see many such Persons there, as would tempt him to ask the Que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stion in the Gospel, <hi>Friends, How?</hi> and for what end <hi>came you hither, not having on the Wedding Garment</hi> of Sincerity and Loyalty.</p>
            <p>Men that are Conversant in the Polices of Nations tell us, that tho' 'tis fit and commendable, that there be a <hi>Reconciliation</hi> betwixt the <hi>King</hi> and his <hi>Quondam Enemies;</hi> yet they ought not in respect of the <hi>Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> or <hi>Themselves,</hi> to be admitted into places of <hi>Trust,</hi> or the <hi>Manage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> of great Affairs; because in despite of Fate, while <hi>Men</hi> are <hi>Men,</hi> there will such <hi>Jealousies</hi> arise, as will clog the Freedom and Confi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence, that ought to be between them. On the behalf of the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment 'twill be objected, that too much <hi>Credulity</hi> encourages an <hi>Abuse,</hi> and <hi>trusting</hi> a reconcil'd Enemy, In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vites an Injury; for <hi>History</hi> is very pregnant with Examples of Men that have had Indempnity for one Fault, and have been taken in Ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther with their <hi>Pardons</hi> in their Poc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kets, before the Ink was scarce dry upon the Parchment; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore we ought not to <hi>Confide,</hi> where the Experiment is so <hi>Dangerous.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>On the other part it will be said, That in common Prudence our <hi>Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditious Interpositors,</hi> ought not to <hi>desire</hi> to be trusted, or intermedle with the Publick, because Men can never <hi>Love,</hi> where they have given too great cause to <hi>Fear,</hi> and will al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>was <hi>Distrust,</hi> where they know they have <hi>injured,</hi> beyond a possibility of <hi>Reparation.</hi> For tho' the King out of a principle of Vertue and Honour may <hi>Forgive,</hi> yet their <hi>Guilt</hi> will not suffer them to <hi>believe</hi> he can, and that will hurry them upon Oblite rating their former Crimes, by re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peating new Offences; both which, being seriously considered, 'tis an Argumant, that those that <hi>Thrust</hi> themselves into Business, whom a <hi>praevious</hi> disposition will not suffer to be <hi>just</hi> or <hi>Hearty</hi> in it, they may make themselves Odious to their Superious, by their <hi>Haughtiness,</hi> and a <hi>Restless</hi> course of Factious <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petitions,</hi> but never will or can, do their King and Country Service.</p>
            <p>But let these things be as they will in the <hi>Theory,,</hi> and like general Rules be liable to <hi>particular</hi> Excep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, yet 'tis Notorious, that since those <hi>that might not have what King they would, have join'd with those that would have None;</hi> and since the Name of <hi>Jacobites</hi> has Walk'd un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:44100:10"/>
               <hi>less</hi> Offensive Names, or has been <hi>Obscur'd,</hi> by <hi>Mixing</hi> in <hi>Clubbs</hi> and other <hi>Meetings,</hi> with the Old Enemies of the Kingdom; there has been greater <hi>Incroachments</hi> upon his Majesties Prerogatives, than ever was before. More <hi>Defamatory</hi> Speeches and Prints against his Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, more <hi>Fears</hi> and <hi>Jealousies</hi> created, more unjust Suspicions Raised; and <hi>less</hi> dutiful acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledgments of the Kings <hi>care</hi> and goodness to his People made at such Assembles, than the King has <hi>deser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved,</hi> or becomes <hi>English</hi> Men in E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minent Stations to be <hi>Guilty</hi> of.</p>
            <p>How have these Seditious Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers we are talking of, <hi>Embarras'd</hi> all our Affairs, and put a <hi>Stop</hi> to every Good motion, by endeavour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to raise a <hi>Misunderstanding</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>twixt the <hi>King,</hi> and his <hi>People,</hi> and render him <hi>Suspected at home;</hi> that as the Champion of <hi>Christendom,</hi> has <hi>Meritted,</hi> and <hi>Received,</hi> the <hi>Applau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ses, Honour,</hi> and <hi>Esteem</hi> of all the World abroad?</p>
            <p>O abominable Ingratitude, Sence<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>less Deportment, and Unpardonable Retribution, to think that the King would be at such a vast Expence, and <hi>Hazard</hi> his Life, to pull down the <hi>Tyranny</hi> of King <hi>James,</hi> to set up a <hi>Despotick</hi> Power of his own? What <hi>Reason</hi> is there to bolt out such <hi>Ugly</hi> Suggestions, and hint such <hi>Spiteful</hi> Reflection, against the Kings Person and Government? Has His Majesty given us any Reason to <hi>Suspect</hi> the commuance of his Goodness; or that he will be <hi>less</hi> kind in preserving our Rights and Privileges, than he was in <hi>Procuring</hi> them, when they were almost <hi>lost,</hi> and setling them so by Law, That it might be <hi>Impossible</hi> for any to <hi>Injure</hi> us for the future; No, But the Men that in a Litteral Sence, would <hi>turn the World upside down, are come amongst us:</hi> Influence Counsels; Preside in Debates; and carry every thing be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore them: Not by the <hi>Force</hi> of their Reasons, but by the <hi>Strength</hi> of their Numbers; not by the <hi>Good<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness</hi> of what they Advance, but by the Clamours of their <hi>Faction:</hi> Who while they are setting up <hi>themselves,</hi> and carry all things into Ataxy and Confusion, Assume a <hi>Supremacy,</hi> and <hi>Infalibility,</hi> in all their Determina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions; and yet would cover all by saying <hi>they are His Majesty's most Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiful and Loyal Subjects:</hi> But how they will reconcile their <hi>Words</hi> with their <hi>Actions,</hi> and Printed Pamphlets, is worth our Examining, since all their Notions and Contrivances, look with Malevolent Aspects up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on <hi>Monarchy</hi> it self, and from that Original <hi>Taint,</hi> and a Design to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mote themselves, raise Undutiful Suggestions against the <hi>King</hi> in be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing; who, without doubt, if he had deserved less <hi>Love,</hi> they would have paid him more <hi>Fear</hi> and <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verence.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Doctrine of <hi>Curbing,</hi> and <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>straining,</hi> the Power of Princes, when the Administration is in good hands; tho' 'twas only Calculated for the <hi>Ruine</hi> of Mankind; and pleases none but those, who design
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:44100:11"/>by such Flagitious Arts, to gain a <hi>Power</hi> of doing that to <hi>others,</hi> which they pretend to be <hi>afraid</hi> of, from such as <hi>ne're</hi> intend it; yet it was always gloss'd with <hi>Specious</hi> Preten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces; and this method is exactly fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed by our Seditious Interpositors of the <hi>last</hi> Edition, who always ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance what may seem pleasing and Popular, enough to Wheedle Men out of their <hi>Allegiance;</hi> and that is,</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Opposing the Sovereignty of the Prince, with an Imaginary Power in the People to controwl and Govern all things at their own Discretion.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Which can be intended for nothing but <hi>Mischief;</hi> for as in the Common Practice of Mankind, where any So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciety of Men usurp more than is their own, their Neighbours will take greater care to confine them within their just Limits; so when Subjects are Reaching after <hi>Royal Power,</hi> by open <hi>Affronts,</hi> and Unrea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sonable <hi>Demands,</hi> they instruct the King to lay the faster hold, and more assiduously maintain the <hi>Rights</hi> of the Crown; for if <hi>causless</hi> Jea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lousies makes people start from their Obedience, Self-Preservation will also make him <hi>Distrust,</hi> secure him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>self against <hi>Unreasonable</hi> Suspicions, and even compel him to Exert his Prerogative, when in Scandalous Pamphlets and Clubs, it begins to be disputed, in whom it is Invested, and these mutual Suspicions will cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ate endless Contentions.</p>
            <p>In a <hi>Monarchial</hi> Government God's Vicegerency ought not to be <hi>dele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gated,</hi> to any other Head than what is <hi>Anointed,</hi> not unaccountably <hi>scat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter'd</hi> among the Multitude: For as <hi>dividing</hi> a Power which is only safe by being <hi>Intire,</hi> derogates from the King's Superiority, so it is <hi>destructive</hi> to the Peoples Liberty, as it <hi>Intoxi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cates</hi> them, and makes them stagger from one form of Government to a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother, till their Divisions, as a pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nishment of their Fickleness, at last sinks them under an <hi>Absolute Monar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chy.</hi> And therefore this pretence of Exalting a Popular Power, can have no other end, but to creat <hi>Jealou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sies</hi> between the Prince and his Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects: For as they cannot digest the <hi>false</hi> Fears they are decoy'd into, without <hi>Undutiful</hi> Resentments, so the Prince cannot brook <hi>Competitors</hi> in Power and Prerogative. Thus the Seditious play the Members a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst the Mind, in order to the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>struction of the whole Body.</p>
            <p>All <hi>Reservations,</hi> of an Absolute Power in the People, distinct and divided from the Sovereign, does but <hi>nourish</hi> a continual Ferment, <hi>sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port</hi> divers Interests, <hi>fill</hi> the Minds of the People with Sedition, Curio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sity and Pride, and <hi>furnish</hi> Envy and Ambition with plausible <hi>disguises</hi> for their Malice, and the Exaltation of the Factious that promote them; as was evident among the <hi>Romans,</hi> where the <hi>Unlimited</hi> Power of the People was but an <hi>Artifice,</hi> to conci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liate deluded Subjects to the <hi>Tyranny</hi> of the <hi>Senate.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Blessed be God we have a Prince, that neither <hi>does,</hi> nor <hi>intends</hi> to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fringe our <hi>Priviledges,</hi> or deprive us
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:44100:11"/>of our <hi>Rights;</hi> and therefore en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tertains no <hi>remote</hi> Suspicions of his Subjects, from whom he resolves to deserve none; and has given us all the Legal Securities a <hi>Parliament</hi> could ask for our future Peace and Happiness. Why then should any sort of Men deal so <hi>Ill</hi> with him, that has dealt so <hi>Friendly</hi> by us? Why should any Men, though but in Clubs and Coffee-houses, set up a Power in opposition to his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesty's, that has ne're <hi>imploy'd</hi> his Power, but to protect and defend us. And yet God Wot, we have such Ill <hi>Members</hi> among us, that are offended at his <hi>Goodness, Surfeit</hi> on his Favours, and are so <hi>Heart-sick</hi> of <hi>England's Prosperity,</hi> that they use all ways to disturb it! And though the King being a Prince of such Incomparable <hi>Clemency,</hi> that he easily forgets and forgives the boldest <hi>Injuries:</hi> And to <hi>mollifie</hi> their stubborn Tempers, by many Indulgent <hi>Concessions,</hi> has endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour'd to quiet their disorder'd Minds, even to the heights of their own Wishes; yet nothing can pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vail, but the more his Majesty <hi>humours</hi> them, the more Exorbitant they grow, and being <hi>Case-harden'd</hi> against all Obligations of Goodness and Ingenuity, are still in their se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Cabals <hi>crossing</hi> his good In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tensions, <hi>misrepresenting</hi> his Actions, and upon every Idle <hi>Pique,</hi> disco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver their want of <hi>Breeding,</hi> in making the <hi>former</hi> Expressions of their Gratitude, the ground of their present <hi>Ill</hi> treatment of him and in their <hi>Savage</hi> Rants, take shelter in that mismanner'd Sarcasm, <hi>What! Did not we make him King?</hi> As if the Thanks for their Deliverance from <hi>Tyranny</hi> and <hi>Oppression,</hi> and giving what they could not keep, endow'd them with a <hi>Priviledge</hi> of saying what comes uppermost, and doing whatsoever they have a mind to, to promote <hi>Sedition,</hi> in hopes at last the <hi>Faction</hi> may grow too hard for the <hi>Government.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now there is so little in this Pretence, to <hi>support</hi> what they would build upon it; that were it not to <hi>disabuse</hi> the People, whose Names they use against their <hi>Wills,</hi> and to redeem their <hi>Understandings</hi> from being <hi>Captivated,</hi> to such <hi>dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingenious</hi> Interpretations of an Ima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginary Power residing in them, I should never have given the Malice of Seditious Men, the pleasure of taking notice of what they <hi>urge</hi> so <hi>impertinently</hi> and <hi>saucily;</hi> but for the end abovesaid, I will ingage this <hi>Monster</hi> of Ingratitude, and shew, though <hi>King William</hi> is the King of our Choice, which methinks should indear him to us, yet he Governs by a <hi>Right,</hi> superior to that of a Popular Election, unless you will <hi>Exclude</hi> God Almighty from his <hi>Prerogative,</hi> in disposing Crowns and Kingdoms.</p>
            <p>'Tis true, King <hi>William</hi> like all other Princes in the <hi>first</hi> Ages of the World, came to the Crown (without mentioning his Right of Blood) upon the single account of his <gap reason="illegible: page cropped" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:44100:12"/>but for any Set of Men, to draw from thence a pretence to use him <hi>Scurvily,</hi> and Treat him as <hi>Coursly</hi> as if they were his Equals or Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>periors, is <hi>Absurd</hi> and <hi>Rediculous.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>No <hi>Community</hi> whose Consent E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stablishes a <hi>Monarch</hi> over them, can have power <hi>Superior</hi> or <hi>Equal</hi> to that which they have constituted: (provided he does not as the late King and others did, convert his Soveraignty into an Arbitrary Power of Destruction, which in our Case, is not so much as pretended, by the worst of his Majesty's Enemies) For they have <hi>Transferr'd</hi> the Power they had, by <hi>Investing</hi> the King with the Sovereignty by a Legal <hi>Establishment and Recognition;</hi> and after that, 'tis <hi>Unreasonable</hi> and <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tradictory</hi> to Assert they have it in themselves, unless they will make all <hi>Solemn</hi> Oaths, and <hi>Deliberate</hi> Acts, of no Validity. If he be a King he has the <hi>Highest</hi> Power, and all his Subjects, in <hi>Whatsoever</hi> Sphere they move are <hi>below him,</hi> whether Single or Collected. Tho' <hi>Englands</hi> Constitution be a <hi>Mix'd</hi> Monarchy, <hi>'tis a Monarchy:</hi> And though the <hi>Estates</hi> in their proper and Distinct <hi>Orbs,</hi> are <hi>Sharers</hi> in the Government, yet this makes no equality of Power with the King, for then the Government could not be a <hi>Monarchy,</hi> more than an <hi>Aristo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cracy</hi> or <hi>Democracy:</hi> And therefore <hi>Wisely</hi> has the Constitution <hi>Temper'd</hi> this Affair, to prevent <hi>Contention</hi> and <hi>Parity;</hi> in Investing the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>narch with a Sovereignty so <hi>discaset<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly</hi> qualify'd, as he may not destroy the <hi>Mixture,</hi> nor the People with such a Power as might render the Monarchy <hi>Titular</hi> and <hi>Precarious;</hi> but that their just measures of <hi>Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stance</hi> and <hi>Duty,</hi> might preserve the Body Politick in Health, Peace and Vigour. Hence it is that the King is call'd our <hi>Leige,</hi> that is our Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Sovereign, and we his <hi>Leige,</hi> that is, his <hi>Lawful</hi> Subjects, and as such, can have no claim above it.</p>
            <p>But that which puts an end to this Saucy <hi>Taunt</hi> and its absurd <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sequence</hi> of Opposing the <hi>Power</hi> of the <hi>People</hi> to the King's <hi>Supremacy,</hi> because their Consent was necessary to his Royal Installation, is what St. <hi>Paul</hi> urges as the principal Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive to <hi>Obedience, viz.</hi> That the <hi>Apex Potestatis</hi> the power of Governing, regularly imploy'd is of <hi>Divine</hi> In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stitution, the <hi>Ordinance</hi> of God, not only as <hi>permitted</hi> by his <hi>Providence,</hi> but as <hi>appointed</hi> by his <hi>Will:</hi> That the <hi>Eternal</hi> is the Sovereign <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prietor</hi> of Kingdoms, and though he make use of Men to settle them, according to the Method his <hi>Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence</hi> directs, yet the <hi>Act</hi> is Gods, and the King's <hi>Authority</hi> is from him, by a <hi>Superior</hi> Character, than what the Populace can pretend to. So though the <hi>Estates</hi> of the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion did confer the <hi>Sovereignty</hi> on King <hi>William,</hi> they were but the <hi>Instruments</hi> and <hi>Agents,</hi> for the <hi>Power</hi> and <hi>Right</hi> of transferring Kingdoms from one King to ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, as from <hi>Saul</hi> to <hi>David,</hi> or from <hi>James</hi> the Second to King
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:44100:12"/>
               <hi>William</hi> the Third, <hi>comes from God,</hi> who is <hi>Judge in these Superior Causes, and puts down one King and sets up another,</hi> and has such an <hi>Interest</hi> in disposing <hi>Power,</hi> that none must pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to but himself. And though Men may chuse the <hi>Person,</hi> his <hi>Power</hi> is derived from God, more peculiarly than from the <hi>Giddy Mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titude, for by him Kings Reign, and Princes decree Justice.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And this is more <hi>particularly</hi> King <hi>William</hi>'s Case, than we shall com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly meet withal in <hi>History.</hi> For though King <hi>William</hi> delivering the Nation from <hi>Popery</hi> and <hi>Slavery,</hi> the People were <hi>Just,</hi> and gave him what he <hi>Earn'd;</hi> yet 'twas the <hi>Power</hi> and <hi>Goodness</hi> of God Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mighty in enabling him to do the Work which <hi>deserv'd a Crown,</hi> that pointed him out to the <hi>Reward,</hi> and as it were <hi>Adorn'd</hi> his Head with a <hi>Glory,</hi> and mark'd him out with such an <hi>Illustrious</hi> Character of <hi>Merit</hi> to the People, that they could not <hi>Miss</hi> him in their <hi>Choice;</hi> but must take him as the King <hi>already Chosen by God,</hi> by such Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vidential <hi>Occurrences,</hi> that in Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon <hi>Gratitude</hi> to his Majesty, or their own future <hi>Safety,</hi> they could not overlook him; and now ought to <hi>Respect</hi> and <hi>Honour</hi> him as sin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceerly, as if an immediate <hi>Voice</hi> from Heaven had plac'd him in the <hi>Vacant</hi> Throne, and said, This is my <hi>Vicegerent.</hi> His <hi>Power</hi> there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore seems to be the <hi>Express</hi> De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signation of God Almighty, and ought not to be <hi>sully'd</hi> by any Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tribute <hi>below</hi> that Original, but <hi>Own'd</hi> and <hi>Rever'd</hi> as a Participati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the <hi>Divine Sovereignty,</hi> as was intended by God, when he first for the good of Mankind put them un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der Government; which being the Doctrine of the <hi>Bible,</hi> destroys all Inferior <hi>Competitions,</hi> and stops the Mouth of <hi>Clamorons</hi> and <hi>Saucy</hi> Up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>braiders; unless they will set up for <hi>Atheists</hi> as well as <hi>Anarchists,</hi> and by <hi>Forestalling</hi> us from fearing God, and Honouring the King, by abusing Words, significant in their meaning, <hi>would neither leave us a God to Fear, nor a King to Honour.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Another <hi>Source</hi> of our Discon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents and <hi>Ill</hi> Treatments of his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesty, ariserh from a <hi>Scandalous</hi> Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stom of Censuring the Actions of our Prince, keeping up <hi>Calumnies</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst the Court, and misrepre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>senting the Government, as if it were in Confederacy to destroy the <hi>Liberties</hi> and <hi>Priviledges</hi> of the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject; which <hi>English</hi> Men are al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways so Tenacious of, that they too greedily imbibe such false <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ports,</hi> without Examming from what sort of Men they come, or their <hi>Design</hi> in Publishing them; which if they would give themselves leasure to <hi>Scrutinize,</hi> they would soon dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover 'twas but the <hi>Artifice</hi> of De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signing Seditious Medlers, to kindle <hi>Jealousies,</hi> and inflame the Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thinking <hi>Croud</hi> into Ill Words, Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>patience, and Distemper, and set them a lingring after more <hi>Liberty</hi> than they know how to use, to make way for <gap reason="illegible: page cropped" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <pb n="20" facs="tcp:44100:13"/>
            <p> Publick <hi>Good</hi> and the <hi>Liberty</hi> of the Subject, are two <hi>Excellent</hi> Words, when they are <hi>Honestly</hi> Used, and <hi>Peaceably</hi> Intended; but are <hi>Tender</hi> Points, and <hi>Cautiously</hi> to be Insisted on, lest <hi>Seditious</hi> Men make use of it to taint their <hi>Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>legiance.</hi> And that this is the <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sign</hi> now on Foot; will appear by taking a view of the <hi>Liberty</hi> that is contending for, by the <hi>Mix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture</hi> of Various Interests against the Government; and it will soon ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear, not to be a <hi>Freedom</hi> from <hi>Arbitrary</hi> Impositions, <hi>Illegal</hi> Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>actions, and other <hi>Ill</hi> Effects of a <hi>Despotick Power;</hi> for these things are not pretended, no, but 'tis a Seditious <hi>Belluine Liberty</hi> of saying, and doing what they please, that is strugling for. Not the <hi>Liberty</hi> that our Fore-Fathers fought for, that was bounded by the <hi>Laws</hi> of Order and <hi>Publick</hi> Good, but a <hi>Liberty</hi> of Contention, a <hi>Liberty</hi> of Publishing <hi>Malicious</hi> Suggestions, and <hi>False</hi> Representations of things, that may be <hi>serviceable</hi> to the Facti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on! A Liberty to <hi>Affront</hi> the King, to <hi>Incroach</hi> upon his Prerogative, to <hi>Lessen</hi> his Power, and <hi>Subject</hi> the Rights of his Sovereignty, to the <hi>Caprichio</hi>'s of every <hi>Angry</hi> In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>truder into <hi>Publick</hi> Societies, and a Liberty of <hi>Improving</hi> and <hi>Practi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing</hi> upon <hi>Fears</hi> and <hi>Possibilities,</hi> till they have brought us in Vassalage to themselves; whose Hot and Fiery <hi>Spirits,</hi> acting upon <hi>False</hi> Suggesti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, can have no other <hi>Design</hi> but to Amuse and Confound us; and therefore the best way to sheild our Selves from the <hi>Danger</hi> and <hi>Delu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion,</hi> is to Judge of the <hi>Designs</hi> by the <hi>Men</hi> that promote them; for all the <hi>Arts</hi> Imploy'd by our <hi>known</hi> Enemies, though never so Artifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cially <hi>Disguis'd,</hi> under the speci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Terms of <hi>Good</hi> Offices to <hi>Publick,</hi> that are but the <hi>Sly</hi> Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>positions of <hi>Cunning</hi> Knaves upon <hi>Credulous</hi> Fools, to advance their own Party: And for that Reason, when we see Ill Men take up a Fit of <hi>Kindness</hi> for their Country, and appear better natur'd than consists with their <hi>Principles</hi> and avow'd <hi>Interests,</hi> 'tis time to suspect a <hi>Fraud,</hi> and weigh their <hi>Words</hi> with their <hi>Practices,</hi> before we trust them fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther than consists with our <hi>Safety;</hi> for the <hi>Men</hi> and their <hi>Designs</hi> can never be parted.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Liberty</hi> is the greatest <hi>Glory</hi> of the People; yet if it be not bound<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Laws of <hi>Reason</hi> and <hi>Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretion,</hi> 'tis the greatest <hi>Make-bate</hi> in the World, and tends directly to the <hi>Ruine</hi> of every Communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, by the known Rule, <hi>That the best things corrupted, become the worst. Liberty</hi> perverted into Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tention for <hi>Superiority,</hi> in the very Design of the <hi>New Mixture,</hi> is but Trapannig and Deluding Men into Real Slavery; catching them with <hi>Words,</hi> and decoying them into <hi>Nets</hi> and <hi>Snares;</hi> and instead of put<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting Men upon considering every thing in its <hi>Proper</hi> place, and one thing with Relation to another, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the <hi>Reason, Weight</hi> and
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:44100:13"/>
               <hi>Importance</hi> of the Action, before we proceed to Censure, it Indul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges Intemperate <hi>Heates</hi> and <hi>Hear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>says,</hi> and by the very Methods, whereby Men think to <hi>Assert</hi> their Liberties, they are taught by Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditious Men to <hi>Destroy</hi> them, for there is no such thing in the World as <hi>Absolute Freedom.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Another cause, why Men are not pleas'd with the Government they live under, but by a continual indea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour to <hi>Subvert</hi> the Sovereign power, disturb it with Sedition, is a desire of <hi>Immunity</hi> from punishment, in such persons whose <hi>Crimes</hi> have ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred them <hi>obnoxious</hi> to Laws; for it being impossible, as long as Men are Subject to <hi>Passions,</hi> but such Faults will be <hi>Committed,</hi> as the Sovereign Power thinks fit to <hi>pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nish;</hi> the Persons who have Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted those <hi>Fautls,</hi> will indubitably seek to avoid the <hi>Punishment,</hi> by raising a Party able to resist the So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veraign Power. And as Criminals seek to avoid punishment for Crimes <hi>already</hi> Committed, so those who know they are laying designs to promote themselves, and their Party, which are contrary to Law, and therefore cannot arrive at their <hi>Ends,</hi> but by invading other Mens <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prieties;</hi> they will <hi>disturb</hi> the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, that they may find <hi>Secu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity</hi> in those Crimes, which for the future they <hi>Resolve</hi> to Commit; and this they always attempt, by gaining Credit enough with the People, to Impose a Cheat upon them, by making use of the Names of <hi>Religion</hi> or <hi>Liberty,</hi> or some o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther like <hi>Specious</hi> Pretence to Gull them; and to this End there is a Faction now among us, that to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mote Fears and Jealousies, lately bag'd their <hi>Pamphlets</hi> about the Streets, <hi>Abusing</hi> the King under the Name of the Court; and upbrading and reviling the last Parliament, as if they had been the worst of Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kind; but this we thought was only a Liberty, taken in His Majesty's <hi>Absence,</hi> and the Interval between the Old and New-Parliaments, from whom we were in great Expecta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, and hoped that the Kings Return, and their Session, would put an end to these Extravagances, and Unite all People in the true Interest of the Kingdom, and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moting the Advantages of a happy Peace, to which their Representa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives were invited, by His Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sty's Most Gracious Speech, fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing.</p>
            <q>
               <pb n="25" facs="tcp:44100:14"/>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="speech">
                        <opener>
                           <salute>My Lords and Gentlemen,</salute>
                        </opener>
                        <p>
                           <hi>I</hi> Have no doubt, but you are met together, with Hearts fully dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>posed, to do what is Necessary for the Safety, Honour, and Happiness of the Kingdom; and that is all I have to ask of You.</p>
                        <p>In order to this, Two things seem Principally to Require Your Conside<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration.</p>
                        <p>The One is, What Strength ought to be Maintained at Sea, and What Force kept up at Land for this Year; All I shall observe to, upon this Head, is, That the Flourishing of Trade, The Supporting of Credit, and the Quiet of Peoples Minds at Home, will de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend upon the Opinion they have of their Security; and to preserve to <hi>England,</hi> the Weight and Influence, it has at present, on the Councils and Affairs abroad, it will be Requisite, <hi>Europe</hi> should see, You will not be wan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting to Your selves.</p>
                        <p>The Second thing I shall mention to You, as of great Consequence, is, The making some further Progress to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards Discharging the Debts, which the Nation has contracted, by reason of the long and Expensive War. In this the Publick Interest, as well as Justice is concerned; and I think an <hi>English</hi> Parliament can never make such a Mistake, as not to hold Sacred all Parliamentary Engagements.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Gentlemen of the House of Commons,</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>I</hi> DO Earnestly Recommend these things to You, That You may provide such Supplies, as You shall Judge Necessary for these several Oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>casions.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>My Lords and Gentlemen,</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>I</hi> Think it would be happy, if some effectual Expedient could be found for Employing the Poor, which might tend to the great Increase of our Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factures, as well as remove a heavy Burden from the People.</p>
                        <p>I hope also you will Employ your Thoughts about some good Bills, for the Advancement of Trade, and for the further Discouraging of Vice and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faness.</p>
                        <p>The things I have mentioned to you, being of common concern, I cannot but hope for Unanimity and Dispatch.</p>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>But, notwitstanding this Royal and Seasonable Advice, so Patheti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cally Adapted toward the Quieting Peoples Minds at Home, the Sore soon broke our again, at their Sedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tious Clubs, which they frequent both in and out of Parliament, to raise unnatual Heats and Jealousies, and from thence were Artificially Transmitted to <hi>Superior Classes,</hi> to serve the Base and Ungenerous Ends of Ungrateful People, and putting the Nation into Flames of Discontent and
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:44100:14"/>Divisions. These Meetings, as they Influence other Actions, are the <hi>Sinks</hi> that pollute our <hi>Fountains,</hi> the <hi>Clouds</hi> that scatter <hi>Storms</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong us, and here the Men may be found, as well as in <hi>other Meetings,</hi> from whose primary <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bates</hi> and <hi>Resolutions,</hi> we expect all the succeeding <hi>Ills</hi> that attend us, from the <hi>Bold Strokes</hi> at Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>narchy that are made in other Pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces; and as the small <hi>Cells</hi> in <hi>Rome,</hi> are said to <hi>Contrive</hi> and <hi>Determine</hi> Affairs, before they are brought into the <hi>Conclave,</hi> and that they who would know what will be done by the <hi>Cardinals,</hi> must con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sult some of the <hi>Minor Fryars;</hi> so there is such a <hi>Correspondence</hi> and Mutual <hi>Agreement</hi> between these <hi>Seditious Clubs</hi> and their <hi>Brethren,</hi> in other <hi>Privilege Places</hi> in the Kingdom, that he that knows what's <hi>Concluded</hi> on in one Place, may know what will be done in the other. For these Clubs being com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pos'd of a Mixture of Men, who having <hi>sower'd</hi> all the generosity of <hi>Nature,</hi> make it their Business to Calumniate the <hi>Best,</hi> and Misin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form the <hi>Worst</hi> of Men; and have to that end, <hi>Insinuated</hi> themselves so far into the Societies of those, that would be thought <hi>Angeli A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gentis in Rebus Humanis,</hi> the great Intelligences in Humane Affairs, that they have twisted their <hi>Interests</hi> to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether, and they have infused a Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verse Spirit into some Men, that what one <hi>Contrives</hi> the other <hi>Acts,</hi> and what's said of one <hi>Meeting</hi> may be understood as the <hi>Designs</hi> of ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny <hi>Others.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>King <hi>William</hi> having done all that <hi>Honest</hi> Men could Wish, or Mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal Man <hi>perform,</hi> for the <hi>Glory</hi> and <hi>Safety</hi> of <hi>England,</hi> a Set of <hi>Envious</hi> Men rose from their several Shades, that had been long in the design of Eclipsing his <hi>Glory;</hi> and like the <hi>Council</hi> that was held by the <hi>Jews</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst our Blessed Saviour, say, <hi>What do we do? This Man does many Mira<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cles, and if we let him alone, all Men will believe on him;</hi> so this late <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termixture</hi> of Men, and Interests a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst His Majesty and Government, seeing every day <hi>fresh</hi> Instances of his Goodness, and Arguments of his <hi>Growing</hi> Glory; in order to their main <hi>Design,</hi> united their Counsels, saying, <hi>What do we do, if we let him alone, all his Subjects will Admire and Love him:</hi> For notwithstanding all our former <hi>Black Arts</hi> to <hi>Disguise</hi> his Virtues, <hi>Blast</hi> his Honour, and <hi>Les<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sen</hi> his <hi>Authority,</hi> we find the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple see through our <hi>Thin</hi> Pretences, the King <hi>Survives</hi> our Scandals, and lives to make us the Common Scorn, and himself the Peoples <hi>Darling.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Let us therefore (say they) take his <hi>Prerogative</hi> a Peg lower, Smite him with our <hi>Tongues,</hi> Wound him with our <hi>Pens,</hi> and Publish it through the Land, that he is not sit to be <hi>trusted</hi> with the Sword: let us raise <hi>Fears</hi> and <hi>Jealousies,</hi> call his Soul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diers a Pack of <hi>Cut-Throats</hi> and <hi>Mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derers</hi> by Profession, and act as fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riously, as if the <hi>Calamities</hi> we pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to fear were felt already, and
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:44100:15"/>from the experience of the <hi>Good</hi> he has done us, raise a <hi>Possibility</hi> of his doing as much against us; and by these <hi>Ways</hi> and <hi>Means,</hi> we shall turn his <hi>Friends</hi> out of the House, pack off his <hi>Dome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sticks,</hi> deprive him of the Peoples <hi>Love</hi> and <hi>Duty,</hi> and accomplish our own <hi>Wishes,</hi> in <hi>Restoring</hi> our Old <hi>Master,</hi> or which is <hi>as well,</hi> Invest our Selves with the <hi>Supream</hi> Authority.</p>
            <p>These were the Pious Resolves at a Club, held I think at the <hi>Old Devil,</hi> and from thence Trans<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted further, and order'd to be Printed and Publish'd in several Pam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phlets; which if I prove, it will be sufficient to convince the World, such <hi>Designs</hi> aginst his Majesty and Government are on Foot; and that there are a <hi>Set of People</hi> amongst us, that Promote and Indulge them, as Copies fit to Immitate.</p>
            <p>And that I may not trouble my Reader in Raking <hi>Old</hi> Dunghils, and searching into <hi>Pamphlets</hi> that are scarce or not to be found; I shall take my Rise no Higher, than the Commencement of the Peace, and begin with a <hi>Pamphlet,</hi> Entituled, <hi>A Discourse concerning Militia's,</hi> where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the Author has Insinuated, that his Majesty is not to be trusted with the Power of the <hi>Sword,</hi>
               <note place="margin">
                  <hi>Page,</hi> 14, 15.</note> and gives his Reasons for it in these Words.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>King</hi> William <hi>by Blood, Relation and other Tyes, and Common Interests, has the House of</hi> Austria, <hi>most of the Princes of</hi> Germany, <hi>and most of the Potentates of the</hi> North <hi>for his Friends and Allies; and can, whatever Interest he joins with.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And is not this a great <hi>Happiness,</hi> to have such a Prince <hi>King</hi> of <hi>England,</hi> that has so many <hi>Powerful</hi> Friends, to Assist him against the <hi>Common</hi> E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nemy. Can our <hi>Aliances</hi> be too great, can our Helps be too many? who could think 'twas in the Power of En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy, to make an Ill construction of so great a Blessing, or that any could suck Poyson, from hese additional Flowers to the Crown of <hi>England;</hi> and yet we see the Clubbers from these Noble Advantages, have con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jur'd up this Jealousy<note n="*" place="margin">Book and Page predict.</note>
               <hi>What security can be gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven, he (meaning the King) will not make use of this Power, to sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>press the Liberties of the People?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Ungrateful people! has not the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curity been given already, in <hi>Deliver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> the Nation when ready to <hi>Sink</hi> in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Ruin, and in <hi>consenting</hi> to such Laws, as a Parliament propos'd for your <hi>safety;</hi> and if after that they de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sired more, 'twas for want of <hi>asking,</hi> if you have it not. Is not the good he has done a <hi>sufficient</hi> security of His Majesty's Integrity, and a <hi>Firm</hi> ground for all his Subjects <hi>Acquie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scence</hi> in his Conduct? Have you any Reason to <hi>Distrust</hi> Him? Can you think that He that ventur'd his Life to <hi>serve</hi> you, can have a thought to <hi>injure</hi> you? Away with these <hi>Idle</hi> Fancies, and <hi>causeless</hi> Jealousies, lest you Tempt Men to think, you want a <hi>greater</hi> Security for your Liberties, than you are fit to be trusted with; and like the <hi>Frozen</hi> Snake, when you'r <hi>warm'd</hi> by an over fond Induldence, you sting your Benefa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor,
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:44100:15"/>which among our <hi>Modern Nur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>murrers</hi> and Seditious Interpositors would go near to find indempnity, under the <hi>undeterminable</hi> name of the <hi>Liberty</hi> and <hi>Privileges</hi> of that sort of People, who in Quest of a <hi>Popular</hi> Omnipotency, pull down all that Opposes it, and <hi>chuckle</hi> every Facti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, whose <hi>Passion Prejudice</hi> and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther <hi>circumstances</hi> contribute most to the carrying on that Design.</p>
            <p>Now Representing the King as a Monarch unfit to be <hi>Trusted,</hi> being the <hi>Topping</hi> Project, and the founda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of all that was to be <hi>Rear'd</hi> up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on it, in order to facilitate their <hi>fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture</hi> purposes: It was agreed at a Succeeding <hi>Club,</hi> which as I take it was held at the young <hi>Devil,</hi> that the forecited Author having a <hi>Grain</hi> or two of modesty too much, for such a <hi>Towering</hi> Design, that an <hi>Abler</hi> Pen at bespattering Kings with in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vented Calumnies, and Suspicions, should draw up their <hi>Reasons,</hi> and Report their <hi>Resolutions</hi> on this Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject, while the <hi>Clubbers</hi> were <hi>Idle</hi> and <hi>Ill</hi> natur'd enough to hear the same; and they having lain a while upon the Table in the <hi>Club</hi> Room afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, where Sedition is as common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly vented, as at the Treason Table in <hi>Newgate, or Tom</hi>'s <hi>Coffee-house,</hi> out comes their Printed Resolves in <hi>Plainer</hi> words and more agreeable to the <hi>Sence of the Party,</hi> under the Title of <hi>A Confutation of the Ballancing Letter;</hi> in which<note n="†" place="margin">Preface and Page the 9th.</note> are these words delivered.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>A standing Army is making the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment Absolute and Arbitrary, and the Nation Slaves. It commands all our Laws, Liberties, and Estates. To put this Power into the Kings Hand, is to lay the whole Nation at his Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretion, and therefore tho we have Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable Thoughts of the King; yet we don't believe he deserves this Trust, nor can manage it Faithfully. That he has neither Merit nor Capacity, to entitle him to so Intire a Confidence; no, not if he had all the Perfections on Earth, as he has a great many; nay, if he were an Angel he was not fit for this Trust,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Are these the products of <hi>your Honourable thoughts of the King?</hi> are these the methods you employ to speak your <hi>gratitude</hi> for his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sties <hi>Redeeming</hi> you from the slave<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry threatn'd, and possessing you of the <hi>Liberty</hi> you are making such very Ill Use of; that can like the man in the Fable blow hot and cold, and with the same Mouth disgorge <hi>Blessing</hi> and <hi>Curssing, Commend</hi> and <hi>Disparage, Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaud</hi> and <hi>Distrust</hi> in the same Breath? are these suggestions the <hi>Honourable ways and means</hi> you <hi>take</hi> like your <hi>Trick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> Predecessors of 48, to make him a <hi>Glorious King?</hi> Blush O Heaven, and let Earth stand Amazed and Tremble! Tell it not in <hi>Gath,</hi> pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lish it not in <hi>Askelon,</hi> lest the <hi>whole</hi> Nation be <hi>Condemn'd,</hi> and <hi>included</hi> in the Guilt of a Few <hi>Seditious</hi> and <hi>Ʋngrateful Members,</hi> that having re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived the benefit of their Delive<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance from his goodness durst not trust him with an Army to De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fend
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:44100:16"/>their Liberties, but would take the Sword from this <hi>Prince,</hi> and force it upon the <hi>People,</hi> from whom, if they Govern themselves by the leading Maxims, and <hi>Humor</hi> now in Vogue and striving to be upper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>most; there is more Danger of a <hi>Rebellion,</hi> than of the Prince's as<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>suming a <hi>Despotick</hi> Power!</p>
            <p>Sure these Gentlemen's <hi>Constitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions</hi> are over Run with the <hi>Scurvy</hi> or <hi>Atra Bilis,</hi> for none see Fantoms and Dread Imaginary Dangers like Hypocondraick Enthusiasts; or else they would ne'er have rais'd such Mean False and Dishonourable <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flections</hi> upon a Prince, whose <hi>Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rits</hi> have given him a Name, Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perior to all the <hi>Titles</hi> upon Earth; and earn'd him the <hi>Intire</hi> Trust, and <hi>Ʋnalienable</hi> Duty of all his Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects.</p>
            <p>What? has not King <hi>William</hi> de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>serv'd this Trust? O Impious Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lumny, Horrible Slander, Ground<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>less Suspition, that is daily confuted by <hi>Experience,</hi> and cold be vended by none but whose <hi>Avowed</hi> De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signs, are for doing <hi>further</hi> Mischief! What's become of the <hi>Old</hi> English Sense of Favours, and Gratitude to Kings that <hi>Delivered</hi> them from Ty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ranny? Is it all dwindled into <hi>Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pular</hi> Caprichio's, and <hi>shrunk</hi> up into <hi>Janisarian</hi> Privilegies? Has ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>empting us from the Fears of <hi>Jailes, Inquisions</hi> and <hi>Smithfield Fires,</hi> caused these clandestine <hi>Reproaches.</hi> Has the Restoring our <hi>Religion,</hi> that ought to be <hi>Dearer</hi> than our <hi>Lives,</hi> deserved no better acknowledge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment? Has the <hi>purchase</hi> of our Peace, and <hi>Liberty</hi> to enjoy it with satisfa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, <hi>merited</hi> no more dutiful re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turns than to affront his Majesty with their causeless Fears, retort his Kindness with hated Jealousies, and sully his Candour with vile Sus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>picion?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Yes,</hi> Replies the Authors of them<note n="†" place="margin">Page 8.</note>
               <hi>we have Trusted the King with all we had. All the Rights of an English King, as the Imperial Crown, with all Dominions, Jurisdistions, Prerogatives, and Preheminencies there unto belonging:</hi> And yet in the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clusion says, <hi>He ought not to be Trusted with the Sword</hi> (which he calls a standing Army, tho the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Author calls it as I do) <hi>for fear of enslaving the Nation:</hi> and in saying that, he might as well have left out all the Rest; for the power of the Sword, which is a very ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tensive Word, is as much the <hi>King</hi>'s <hi>Right,</hi> and as firmly Invested in him <hi>by Law,</hi> as any other of the Appen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dices as the <hi>Crown;</hi> and since there are so many <hi>Lawyers,</hi> that are the Leading men in these <hi>Clubs,</hi> it looks <hi>ill</hi> they should forget it.</p>
            <p>And as to giving the Crown let the Poet answer for me.
<q>
                  <l>As for the Crown you have bestow'd,</l>
                  <l>With all its Limitations:</l>
                  <l>The meanest Prince in <hi>Christen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Would never Stir a Mile from Home,</l>
                  <l>To Govern Three such Nations.</l>
                  <pb n="27" facs="tcp:44100:16"/>
                  <l> For if the Sword from'th King's with held,</l>
                  <l>Which Laws have made his Own:</l>
                  <l>Who knows but when the Megrim works,</l>
                  <l>Such wavering Christians may like Turks,</l>
                  <l>Employ't against the Crown?</l>
               </q>
            </p>
            <p>Self Preservation is a Principle in <hi>Nature</hi> never to be dropt, and by the same rule that men suspect, they give <hi>cause</hi> to be suspected: which is only applicable to those that have rais'd the <hi>Mormo's;</hi> for all the Leige and Loyal Subjects of <hi>England,</hi> that are True, and sted<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fast to the King upon Rules of <hi>Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour,</hi> and <hi>Conscience,</hi> had rather die if occasion should require it, than hear his Majesty <hi>Traduced</hi> or <hi>Suspe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted.</hi> They say His Majesty has <hi>deserved</hi> more than <hi>England</hi> has to give: has <hi>merited</hi> the <hi>Intire</hi> Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fidence and Obedience of his People: and that after all the <hi>Experience</hi> we have had, to grow suspicious of his <hi>Good</hi> Intentions, is to Revile his <hi>Vertues,</hi> grow <hi>weary</hi> of our own happiness, expose our selves to <hi>Dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger,</hi> and Affront the Common <hi>Sence</hi> of mankind.</p>
            <p>But <hi>Seditious</hi> men seldom do their work by halves, and therefore as if it were not sufficient to <hi>Ʋnking</hi> his Majesty, they indeavour to <hi>Ʋnman</hi> him also, by saying <hi>He has no capa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>city for such a Trust:</hi> to which I'll make no answer; for such efforts do not <hi>Blast</hi> but <hi>Brighten,</hi> and they that have the <hi>confidence</hi> to Assert that, will <hi>Boggle</hi> at nothing, therefore like men that deny <hi>first Principles,</hi> they are to be confuted with <hi>Scorn and Taciturnity:</hi> All the World ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mire the strength of his Judgment, Ability of his Mind, and Dexteri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of his Parts, which I dare not undertake to deliniate; for to do it by the <hi>common</hi> Topicks of compari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rison, would be a <hi>Diminution</hi> of his <hi>Greatness,</hi> and to form a just Idea of his Royal <hi>Personal Capacities,</hi> or venture upon his <hi>Character,</hi> requi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>res a Soul as great as his Own, and it would be a Prophanation in any vulgar Hand to attempt it: Silence and Admiration, best commend things above the Sphere of our Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacities.</p>
            <p>Next, to scare People out of their Duties, as 'tis the common practice of all Seditious Conventicles, to ransack Stories for <hi>Memorable Acci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dents,</hi> and <hi>Prodigies,</hi> and having cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culated them for this <hi>Meridian,</hi> a muse people with a superstitious <hi>belief</hi> that the same <hi>Events</hi> must fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low: So our Author (to the credit of his Learning) tells us from Mr. <hi>Knox</hi> a lamentable story, to fright both Sexes out of their Allegiance. <hi>Viz.</hi>
               <note n="†" place="margin">Page 13.</note>
               <hi>That in the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of</hi> Ceilon <hi>there was a King.</hi> Strange! <hi>and that King had a Standing Army too.</hi> Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>digious! <hi>and his Subjects were wont to call him by a name that signified next to God.</hi> Horrible and Dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gerous! <hi>and the people were such slaves, that they durst not speak to him in the first Person</hi> (Singular Number
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:44100:17"/>
               <hi>Preter perfect Tence</hi> and Indicative Mood) <hi>and say, I did so or so, but Baula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gaut the Limb of a Dog did so.</hi> Betray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of their Liberties! <hi>and if the King ask'd'em how many children they had, they swer'd the limb of a Dog has so many an-Puppy-dogs, and so many Bitch Puppies.</hi> Officers and Men that had Places at Court I warrant them! And from this poor crawling Fancy, ridi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culous in its application, and unpar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>donable for its Wit, he takes occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on to fall into a fit of Devotion, and <hi>gives God thanks that we were not born Puppy-dogs:</hi> and I wonder when his hand was in and his eyes up, he did not prescribe the <hi>Remedy</hi> to his Majesties Subjects, to bring the King to Reason, and redress all these Mis-managements and Gre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vances, <hi>viz. Rebellion;</hi> for that he saies <hi>cur'd the King of</hi> Ceilon, <hi>from</hi>
               <note n="*" place="margin">Preface.</note>
               <hi>at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempting to make himself the Rickety Head of a Languishing Body.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This story big with an ill design, as silly as it looks, was strangely <hi>Admir'd</hi> by the <hi>Party,</hi> and tho cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culated for nothing but Fools and Fire-sides, furnished them with new matter against the Court, and the whole Faction was so full of that Whim, that it larded all their Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courses: and you could hear of no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing but of Slavery, and <hi>Baulau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gautizing,</hi> Arbitrary Power and Puppy-dogs. The <hi>Lobby,</hi> the Pain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted-Chamber, and Court of Request Rung with the dull Fancy; and those that were not in the <hi>Mixture,</hi> in the language of our Modern <gap reason="illegible: page cropped" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and <hi>New Converts,</hi> were all Sons of Bitches. Fine language, but this is their way of Arraigning the <hi>Faith</hi> of Kings and frighting <hi>timerous</hi> Souls from their Duty.</p>
            <p>The Great Point of Slandering the King with Jealousies and Sus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>picions being thus far advanced, they re-assume the former debate, about the <hi>Power of the Sword,</hi> and at a Club held I think at the <hi>Rose,</hi> or the the Long-dog at <hi>Westminster,</hi> I am not certain which, the que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stion being put, it was Resolved <hi>Nemine Contradicente,</hi> and publish'd in a Pamphlet called a <hi>Discourse con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning Militia</hi>'s<note n="†" place="margin">Page 6.</note>
               <hi>That nothing is so essential to the Liberties of the people, as placing the Power of the Sword in the Hands of the Subjest.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And now you see what this <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter mixture</hi> of Interests would be at, and what their Pretences of <hi>Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty</hi> amounts to, <hi>viz.</hi> to <hi>tye up the Kings hands, and to Arm their Own</hi> with the power of the Sword, and then <hi>Good Night Land-Lord.</hi> Either we must have one <hi>Popish</hi> King, or Four Hundred <hi>Arbitrary</hi> Sovereignes; and of these two evils which is most <hi>Eligible,</hi> is as great a difficulty to <hi>Determine,</hi> and therefore I'll return. I wonder when these Gentlemens <hi>Pens</hi> were in, or their <hi>Mouths</hi> open in the <hi>Club,</hi> they did not claim the <hi>Crown</hi> also; for that would have stopt many a <hi>Wide</hi> Gap in their Fortunes: and 'tis as <hi>essentially neces<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sary</hi> that they should be both in one <gap reason="illegible: page cropped" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="29" facs="tcp:44100:17"/>a sufficient <hi>Power</hi> to defend it self: For as times go, and Subjects which have found <hi>Protection</hi> from their Prince, and have no just grounds to <hi>suspect</hi> any prejudice from him in their Laws, Liberties, or Estates; yet enter into <hi>Diffidence</hi> of him, and being led by <hi>Passion, False Conse<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quences, Envy, or Ambition,</hi> indea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour to <hi>Subvert</hi> his Government; 'tis <hi>essentially necessary</hi> for his safety that the <hi>Sovereign</hi> Prince should be <hi>Arm'd</hi> with something more than his own <hi>Innocency and Integrity,</hi> to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>press Seditious, Aspiring, and Unrea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sonable Subjects: But to return from this Digression, let me ask these Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen a short Question or two First,</p>
            <p>Since things are not ripe enough yet, for the <hi>Inter-mixture</hi> to tell their <hi>Names,</hi> appear in their own <hi>Dress,</hi> and <hi>say,</hi> if they could <hi>wrest</hi> the Sword out of the hands of <hi>King William</hi> they would restore it to the late King <hi>James:</hi> which tho first in the <hi>Intention</hi> of giving these distur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bances, must be last in <hi>Execution.</hi> I would fain know since their are so many Factions among us, and all tho fit for nothing else imagine they are capacitated to Govern, to what <hi>sort</hi> of people in <hi>England,</hi> they would commit the <hi>Power</hi> they are contending for, and whether they have consider'd the <hi>Impractica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bleness</hi> and <hi>Danger</hi> of this <hi>bafled</hi> Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject. Will they commit it to the Papists, to the Church of <hi>England</hi>-men, the Presbyterians, the Inde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pendents, the Anabaptists, the Fift Monarchists, the Socinians, the Mug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gletonians, or the Quakers; and whether their disappointment would not be equal to their folly. For if they should give it to the <hi>Papists,</hi> they'd Restore it to King <hi>James,</hi> and that would displease, as well as expose the <hi>Williamites.</hi> If they should commit it into the Hands of the stanch <hi>Church of England-men,</hi> they would be sure to give it again to <hi>King William,</hi> and that would en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage the <hi>Jacobites</hi> and <hi>Republicans.</hi> If they should give it to the <hi>Presby<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terians,</hi> they'd keep it <hi>Themselves</hi> and set up a <hi>Common-wealth,</hi> seise the Kings and the Church Lands, and disoblige the <hi>Monarchists</hi> and Epis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>copal Party. If they give it to the <hi>Independants,</hi> instead of beating the <hi>Sword</hi> into Plow-Shares, they'd ham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer it into <hi>bloody Axes.</hi> In short the <hi>Anabaptists</hi> would demean them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves here, as they did to the <hi>Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces</hi> of <hi>Germany.</hi> The <hi>Chiliasts</hi> would keep it in their own hands till <hi>Christ</hi> came; and the <hi>Socinians</hi> would <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>throne</hi> him from being a <hi>King</hi> as well as from being a <hi>God:</hi> the <hi>Muggelto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nians</hi> would bless none but them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves with <hi>Offices,</hi> and Curse all the world besides with <hi>Incapcity</hi> and <hi>Poverty,</hi> and the <hi>Quakers</hi> have been so accustom'd to heave the <hi>Glass</hi> and <hi>Nogging</hi> to their <hi>Heads,</hi> that they'd let the <hi>Sword</hi> drop out of their <hi>hands,</hi> and suffer all (like themselves) to run into <hi>confusion.</hi> And this <hi>Game</hi> having been once plaid already, till each Vigorous Pretender had sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>planted the other, and at last were found to settle on the <gap reason="illegible: page cropped" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="30" facs="tcp:44100:18"/>Monarchy: Till they can Agree where to place it more beneficially to the conservation of our True Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty. <hi>'Tis best to let it remain quiet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly in the hand where it is.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Gentleman that published <hi>Considerations upon the choice of a Speaker,</hi> has told us<note n="†" place="margin">Page 1.</note>'twas the Observation of the Lord <hi>Burleigh,</hi> (and he was counted a very Wise man) <hi>That</hi> England <hi>can never be thoroughly ruin'd but by a Parliament,</hi> and I believe the Antimonarchical Clubbers, who make such despe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate stoops at the <hi>Regal</hi> Power, and would leave his Majesty nothing but an empty Name think so too. For the <hi>F</hi>'s the <hi>H</hi>'s and <hi>Others</hi> that set up for the vanity of Speaking Long and Impertinently, having talk<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed themselves out of <hi>Breath,</hi> and the whole Audience out <hi>Patience,</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout <hi>where the Power should be placed,</hi> the Club came to this Resolution, which is Published in a Virulent Pamphlet, call'd, <hi>Considerations upon the State of the Navy Considered.</hi>
               <note n="†" place="margin">Page 16.</note>
               <hi>That if the Grievances continue, the Commons may at last be forc'd to take the management of the Navy, and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pendant Offices into their own Hands; by appointing Commissioners of their own, and this seems Rational enough, that those that are at the charge, should super<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>intend the management of the Affair.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>All proceedings have their course and train, and by the Wake men steer, you may easily guess to what Port they are Bound. The Designs of these men by their Working, is to <hi>shake</hi> our Fundamental Establish<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and under the appearance of <hi>Liberty,</hi> to shrivel his present Majesty into an Emperor of the Moon, and therefore <hi>trace those</hi> measures in which others of the same kidney were <hi>suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cessful,</hi> in hopes of the same Event, and will run from one degree of Wickedness to another, till they have obtained what they aimed at. Their last demand related to the <hi>Land Force</hi> only, and now to shew they'll ne'er be satisfied with any thing, till they have possessed them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves of <hi>All.</hi> The Management of the <hi>Navy,</hi> and Dependant Offices, must be seis'd into the <hi>Parliaments Hands,</hi> which being agreed on by all sides to be the <hi>Strength of the Kingdom,</hi> you may guess how <hi>unreasonable</hi> they are, and what <hi>usage</hi> his Majesty must expect. See by what <hi>Tricks</hi> they in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>troduce their Scheme of <hi>Subverting</hi> the Government: for as if they be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieved the Lord <hi>Burleigh</hi>'s Notion, what they <hi>Lurch</hi> from the King, they would bestow upon the Parliament for <hi>that end,</hi> and no question but with the same design at bottom of it, as their Fore-fathers had in advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cing the <hi>Rump:</hi> make them their <hi>Tools</hi> to ruin the King, and then turn them out of <hi>Doors,</hi> and erect a Frip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pery of their own. They are ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry kind Souls, and would give the Parliament what they <hi>Won't</hi> accept as they are <hi>Wise</hi> and <hi>Can't</hi> accept, while they continue the Character of being his Majesty's most Loyal and Dutiful Subjects, the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:44100:18"/>Assembled in Parliament.</p>
            <p>This seeming kindness to the <hi>Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament,</hi> is but a Trick of the old Trade, to <hi>Lessen</hi> the King's Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty; for investing the Parliament <hi>with the Supream Authority of</hi> Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, is as great an Error, as the design to make them so is mischie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vous, for they must Meet, and Sit, and Act, as Subjects, and under that denomination, 'tis nonsence to call them <hi>the Supream Authority.</hi> They that would make the Parliament <hi>greater</hi> than they are, do but ridi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cule their <hi>Just Authority;</hi> and new minting phrases, to take away their Subordination, is only intended to raise Heats and Animosities in the Kingdom. I know 'tis one piece of Seditious Mens Policy, to repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sent those that truly love and faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully serve his Majesty as if they were <hi>Enemies</hi> to Parliaments; but herein they act like <hi>Pliny</hi>'s malicious Animals, that had their <hi>Poyson</hi> in their <hi>Tongues,</hi> and their <hi>Gall</hi> in their <hi>Ears,</hi> and will neither speak nor hear but what sets men at variance. There is no body of men so Uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>versally and Absolutely good, that it can be any harm <hi>to wish some of them were better.</hi> Nor is it any dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paragement to mens understandings, to say <hi>they are not always Infallible,</hi> nor no <hi>ill</hi> wish that no men <hi>would act as if they were so.</hi> Our <hi>English</hi> Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liaments are the happiest Constitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion in the World, and notwithstand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing all their <hi>Faults</hi> and <hi>Excises</hi> which have given great <hi>Dissatisfastions</hi> to the considering and sober people of <hi>England,</hi> and have been sometimes very troublesome to the <hi>Supream Authority</hi> by a peculiar <hi>Fondness</hi> of their own <hi>Notions;</hi> yet they are to be had in great Veneration, and will be so by all that understand themselves: Whereas those <hi>Sediti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous</hi> men, that would cloath them with a <hi>Politicial Omnipotency,</hi> and rob the <hi>King</hi> to enrich the <hi>Parliament,</hi> are the greatest Enemies to the Constitution.</p>
            <p>The reason why the Parliament should take upon them the Executive part of the <hi>Government,</hi> as their factious Authors would have them, is because <hi>they that are at the charge ought to super<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>intend the Affair,</hi> which is a Notion so injurious to our <hi>Constitution</hi> that it overthrows the <hi>Structure,</hi> and <hi>le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vels</hi> all before it. For tho' there are some <hi>ill</hi> instructed men, that have boldly disputed for a <hi>Co-ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate</hi> Power in the Parliament; yet till the publication of these resolves no Bayard has been so blind, nor Wretch so impudent (pardon the Expression) as to give them the whole <hi>Executive</hi> part also. Every Parliamentary Address, and all our Laws speak the contrary. For when according to their duty, they have propos'd what is requisite to be done, <hi>they pray his Majesty to take care that it may be Executed,</hi> now the Power these men assume, in dele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gating the King's <hi>Prerogative</hi> to the Parliament, is no less injurious to their <hi>Honour,</hi> than <hi>Prejudicial</hi> to the <hi>King;</hi> for the Inference they suborn to colour the <hi>Presumption,</hi> is no less than if they had said in plain words, <hi>since
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:44100:19"/>you have the power of the King's Purse strings: Puzzle his Affairs: Cross all his Politicks: Tire him with trouble<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>some Tacks: Confound his Ministers with cross purposes: Deny him what you think he desires: Advance whate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver you think will displease him: Take advantages of the necessities of the Crown and Creditors wanting their Money: Keep the Exchequer Poor,</hi> and as the word is, <hi>let him know Who and Who's together: and in fine, compell him to buy supplies at the price of his Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raignty, and Establish your selves per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petual Dictators, the Power's your own and now's the time to Exert it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>What Barbarous Humours, and Unnatural Presumptions govern these Seditious Clubbers, who would <hi>tempt</hi> the Parliament to embarrass the King's Affairs, and take the whole <hi>Administration</hi> of the Government in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to their hands, which is the King's Right by all the Laws of <hi>England,</hi> and because they have a <hi>joint</hi> Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vilege of granting supplies, would invest them with the <hi>Supreme Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority of the Nation,</hi> to controul and govern all things at their discretion, which is an <hi>Error</hi> as great as the design to <hi>promote</hi> or <hi>Engross</hi> it is <hi>Mischievous;</hi> for the Parliaments have no such <hi>Ʋnlimited</hi> Power, and only act in <hi>concurrence</hi> with the King. For as the King cannot raise <hi>Taxes</hi> with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out consent of Parliament, so the <hi>Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament</hi> cannot do it without the King. <hi>Laws</hi> do not take their <hi>Obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging</hi> Force from the Quality of those that Devise them; but from the <hi>Regal Power</hi> that enlivens them from Dead Letters into speaking <hi>Laws.</hi> 'Tis the Royal <hi>Le Roy Le Veult, the King will have it so,</hi> which is the Imperative Sentance that gives ev'ry Law a Being, and is Pronounced in <hi>Passing</hi> every Act of Parliament. So that these bold Donatives and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands, Illegal Suppositions, and Ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>xatious Disputes, are so far from asserting the Peoples <hi>Right,</hi> as is pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended, that they utterly <hi>destroy</hi> them by unwarrantable <hi>Encroachments</hi> and <hi>Additions,</hi> and in the whole are but the <hi>froth of Seditious Intermedlers,</hi> the Transports of wild desires, and the Gratification of some unreasonable Men, <hi>that never did, nor never will do good to</hi> England, <hi>till they govern them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves by better Principles, and prove their Conversions real, by more Loyal Practices.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Hitherto I have only shew'd you what the <hi>Mixture of various Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rests</hi> have been <hi>Plotting,</hi> towards the Accomplishing their <hi>Main</hi> design of <hi>Subverting</hi> the Government, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ducing the Nation into a State of War and Confusion, which some will think are Crimes too <hi>Black</hi> to be heard of among Christians; but so degenerate is the Age, and so A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bominably Wicked are this sort of of People, that that which precedes is nothing to the <hi>Tragical</hi> Scene that that is open'd in the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forecited Pamphlet<note n="†" place="margin">P. 13, 14.</note>
               <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Government is built upon this Foundation, that Kings are accounta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to their Subjects, and that upon Fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>falture, of their own Free Will and Power, they may proceed to a new E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lection,
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:44100:19"/>and place one more Righteous upon the Throne.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Bold and Impudent Assertion, and as far from <hi>Truth</hi> in the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sign of our Laws, as light is from darkness, and the Club that vomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted up this <hi>Position,</hi> and the Men that do Comment upon it by their <hi>Practices,</hi> act like People <hi>spotted</hi> with the Plague, being <hi>Incurable</hi> themselves they have yet the pleasure left of Infecting others, which I shall en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavour to Antidote by shewing that <hi>Extraordinary</hi> Proceedings are not to be produced as <hi>Presidents,</hi> but upon the same occasions, for the Laws of <hi>England</hi> have taken such care of the King, and his Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, that they have made his Person <hi>Sacred,</hi> and his Rights <hi>Invoilable;</hi> but that I suppose which misleads people into that pernicious Error, is <hi>Misconstruing</hi> the Proceedings a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst the late King, which is as full a confutation of that Principle, as can be imagined, if rightly ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prehended. For that the <hi>Honourable Convention</hi> might not seem to make Dangerous <hi>Presidents</hi> to Posterity, give the people a <hi>Scandalous</hi> Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity, or render the Monarchy of <hi>England Precarious,</hi> and not worth Acceptance; they Cautiously and Honestly avoided such <hi>Pretences,</hi> and settled the Nation<note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>Vid.</hi> Vote of the Conventi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, of <hi>Jan.</hi> 28. 1688.</note> upon <hi>the Express Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nounciation of James the Second, his voluntary with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drawing himself out of the Kingdom, and the Necessity of provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding for the Nation when the Throne was Vacant,</hi> and therefore would ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver depart from the words <hi>Abdica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion</hi> and <hi>Vacancy of the Throne.</hi> So that what the <hi>Convintion</hi> did upon that Extraordinary Occasion, was when the late King went hence, but shutting the door after him, which the <hi>Mixture</hi> of Various In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terests are now endeavouring to open, with <hi>Pick locks</hi> of their own inventing, and I question not, but if they had <hi>Power</hi> to their <hi>Will,</hi> they would make use of <hi>Betty</hi>'s also. For, whereas some modester Men build this Popular Notion only, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on a King's open violation of the <hi>Original Contract,</hi> converting his <hi>So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vereignity</hi> into a power of <hi>Destru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction</hi> and restrain that also to Cases <hi>Apparent, Evident, and Certain,</hi> these wretched Men, having none of these things to pretend against King <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam,</hi> threaten the Nation with the <hi>Dissolution</hi> of their <hi>Monarchy,</hi> for no other cause than the <hi>Mismanagements</hi> of the Ministery and for that reason only say,<note n="*" place="margin">Page 14.</note>'tis time <hi>to think of ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther form of Government,</hi> which sums up their <hi>Designs</hi> in a few words, and calls for a Parliamentary Preventi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, lest men under the apprehension of the Danger threatned, should be tempted to think <hi>that the Evils they neglect they tolerate,</hi> which God for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bid!</p>
            <p>Having thus discover'd the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signs of the <hi>Mixture,</hi> let us look in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the Causes they Assign to <hi>justifie</hi> their Practices. And here I incoun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter such palpable <hi>Contradictitions,</hi>
               <pb n="34" facs="tcp:44100:20"/>that would give me more trouble to find out a <hi>Method, than Matter</hi> to refute them, if I were not obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged to them for prescribing one, Fears, Jealousies, and Suspicions, are the unhappy Parents of their Lewd proceedings against his Majesty and Government, and yet almost in the same breath, confess they are <hi>secur'd</hi> from all apprehensions of Danger during <hi>his Reign.</hi> So that by their own acknowledgement, their <hi>Fears are foolish, their Jealousies caufless, their Suspicion Ʋndeserved,</hi> and makes it my task to <hi>prove</hi> them so, which I shall do very briefly.</p>
            <p>'Tis a true, but unhappy Chara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cter of a particular Reigning Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction against Monarchy, that they are so given to <hi>Leasing,</hi> that though they had truth on their side, yet 'twould never please them, 'till they had <hi>dress'd</hi> it up, and <hi>set</hi> off, with all the colours of <hi>Folly, Falshood,</hi> and <hi>Calumny,</hi> and in much larger mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sure must we expect these additions, when all these joyn'd with pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judice promotes them. What can we think more <hi>Ridiculous,</hi> than spreading insinuations <hi>that the King is not in the Interest of his People,</hi> which is such a plain <hi>Contradiction,</hi> they might as well have said he was <hi>divided from himself.</hi> For their own Consciences, if they have any, and they would give them leave to speak, must say that in all the Circum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stances of his Majesty's History, he has so <hi>Abated</hi> his own <hi>Grandeur,</hi> so <hi>bountifully</hi> scatter'd his <hi>Favours</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongst us, and so <hi>little</hi> considered himself, that no King ever did so much, no mortal Man could <hi>do more,</hi> to convince the World, that as he had no other Intentions in his co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming hither, than to preserve our Religion, Laws, and Liberties; so it has been his endeavour ever since, by a Just Administration, and even Ballancing all Interests at home, and exposing his dear Life Abroad, to advance the Welfare and Glory of the Nation, as you might have heard from his Royal Mouth, in his most graicous Answer to the Commons, Address'd <hi>March</hi> 25. 1699.</p>
            <p>
               <q>I came hither to restore the An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient Constitution of this Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; I have had all possible re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gard to it since my coming, and I am resolved through the course of my my Reign to endeavour to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>serve it intire in all the parts of it, I have a full confidence in the Affections of my people, and I am well assured they have the same in me, and I will never give them Just Cause to alter their Opini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons. It shall be my study, to the utmost of my Power, to perform the part of a Just and Good King: and as I will ever be strictly and nicely careful of observing my Promises to my Subjects, so I will not doubt of their Tender Regards to me.</q>
            </p>
            <p>Let all his Majesties Actions be tryed with the <hi>stricktest</hi> Scrutiny, and if they be taken as they ought, in <hi>coherence</hi> with his Great Design of
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:44100:20"/>
               <hi>preserving</hi> the Honour and safety of the Nation: his whole Life will ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear <hi>Just</hi> and <hi>Equitable;</hi> but if men will lay their false invented <hi>Fears,</hi> at the Doors of his Royal Palace, that were begot and nourish'd in their own <hi>Houses,</hi> and catch here and there a <hi>snap,</hi> without examining the <hi>Reason, Ʋse</hi> and <hi>End</hi> of every Action, which also by the way may not be fit for them to know neither: for every head is not fit to Pry in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the Closet of Princes. <hi>Reasons</hi> and <hi>Maxims</hi> of State, are above their reach, and looking upward will but turn their <hi>Brains,</hi> and make their Heads <hi>Giddy,</hi> which are too much afflicted with the <hi>Megrim</hi> al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready. I say, if they proceed so clandestinly, they may run into an <hi>Eternal</hi> circulation of Jealousies, Slander the Best Government in the world, and make <hi>Quidlibet ex Quo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>libet,</hi> find Treason in the Laws, and pick Blaphemy out of the Holy Bible.</p>
            <p>Let the King's Enemies if they can, give us one <hi>single</hi> instance, wherein he has not been Just to the <hi>Constitution?</hi> What Law has he broken? what Rights of the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple has he <hi>Invaded?</hi> what new Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tences of Prerogative has he <hi>Inven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted?</hi> or wherein has his Majesty <hi>stretch'd</hi> those that are the known, and allow'd <hi>Rights</hi> of his Crown, to the <hi>prejudice</hi> of his Subjects? or what has he omitted that might conduce to their Happiness? Did the King ever stop his Ears to any <hi>Reasonable</hi> Petition? did he ever <hi>deny</hi> Justice to the meanest Subject? or <hi>refuse</hi> shewing mercy where it was needful? No, In his Majesty they have nothing to revil but his <hi>Vertues,</hi> and were it fit to mingle his <hi>Glory</hi> with the <hi>Jealousies</hi> of the <hi>Mixture,</hi> they could never be so <hi>perfectly</hi> summ'd up, as in their Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>posites.</p>
            <p>How unreasonably do men argue, that would make <hi>Jealousies Conje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctures, Hear says, Fancies,</hi> and <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ports,</hi> a ground to raise <hi>suspitions</hi> upon, against a King, whose Life and Actions confound all such pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tences: and yet such <hi>Brutes</hi> are found among us, that notwithstand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing all his Majesties Bountiful <hi>conce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ssions,</hi> raise evil surmises, and make Seditious Comments and Ungreatful Returns to his Goodness, for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>get their Obligations, by growing <hi>weary</hi> of their Duty, and would per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>swade the world that the King is not in the Interest of his <hi>People,</hi> because they are in none but their <hi>Own.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And now having answered the first Cause they assign as the Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son of their Fears, I proceed to the next: which is as <hi>Ʋnreasonable</hi> and <hi>Ridiculous,</hi> as the former is <hi>false</hi> and <hi>scandalous,</hi> and both confute themselves.</p>
            <p>Those <hi>Pseudo Patriots</hi> that by Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proving and Practising upon Fears and possibilities, would cover the Affronts and Indignities they put upon his Majesty, confesses there is no danger to be expected during
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:44100:21"/>his Reign, and give these <hi>substantial</hi> Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons for it<note n="†" place="margin">Argument a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst a Standing Army <hi>p.</hi> 9.</note>
               <hi>Because he is our Moses, and has delivered</hi> England <hi>from a Captivity, equal to that of the Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren of Israel. A Prince whose Life is so necessary to the Preservation of</hi> Europe, <hi>that both Protestant and Popish Princes, forgeting their anci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent Maxims, and innate Animosities, made it their Common Interest to chose him their Patron and Protector: a Prince in whom we know no Vices: but what have been esteemed Vertues in others,</hi> viz. His <hi>undeserved clemency to his Enemies, and his too much exposing</hi> that <hi>Life, upon which depends not only our Safety, but the Libertties of all</hi> Europe, <hi>and the Protestant Religion through the World:</hi> and yet to spoyle their kindness, usher in an Inference, that tells the Reader they give no credit to their own Elogies, for after they said, <hi>If this most Excellent Prince was as Immortal as his Glorious Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, we ought in Common Prudence, to abandon all thoughts of self Preser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation, and wholly rely on his Care and Conduct.</hi> They are pleas'd to add what was the mighty Argument of their Party in another Place; <hi>that since no Vertue, nor Pitch of Glory, can exempt him from paying the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Debt to Nature, we ought not to Intrust any Power with Him which we don't think proper to be continued to his Successor!</hi> A poor shift God Wott to support Ingratitude, and might have been better solv'd by agreeing to be Civil to him during his Life, than by making his Mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tality an Argument for the exercise of ill manners, promoting Fears and Jealousies, and aspiring after his So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vereignity; for by these Policies the <hi>Intermixture</hi> Work, that say in effect not this <hi>King,</hi> but <hi>Another</hi> King, or a Form of Government <hi>that would have no King in Israel, that the</hi> Seditious <hi>might do what was Right in their own Eyes, act like men of Authority and not as the Scribes;</hi> for then they will want no Colla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teral Security for their <hi>Privileges,</hi> when their Reasons are in their <hi>Own Hands,</hi> and the <hi>Supreme</hi> Power placed in that sort of ill natur'd People, whose understandings grow downward, and affront a Good King in <hi>Being,</hi> because 'tis possible a <hi>Bad one</hi> may come hereafter, which is an absurdity never equall'd, but by those Members of the same Club, that affirm'd among other Debates and Resolutions<note n="*" place="margin">Arg. cont. Stand. Army <hi>p.</hi> 28.</note>
               <hi>that the most likely way of re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>storing King</hi> James, <hi>is maintaining an Army to keep him out:</hi> Or a Gentleman that said, the late noise of an Invasion from <hi>France,</hi> was a trick of the <hi>French King</hi>'s to keep up a Standing Army in <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>To slander his Majesty in his Honour, and the good esteem of his People, not for any thing he has done, or that they fear he will do, <hi>but for what possibly another King may do hereafter,</hi> is either a senceless or a very malicious way of argu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and makes all their <hi>Panegyricks</hi>
               <pb n="37" facs="tcp:44100:21"/>on the King, look as if they were form'd from the deepest <hi>Malice,</hi> and <hi>Prejudice,</hi> and were only the Arts of the <hi>Mixture,</hi> under Profession of the greatest <hi>Veneration,</hi> to diminish the Person they pretend to magni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie, and to use their own words, is <hi>cuting a Mans Throat with a Fea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther:</hi> for tho a preventional Pru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence in stifling ill consequences in their <hi>Causes,</hi> and obviating mischiefs in the <hi>Bud</hi> is very commendable; yet to make a danger <hi>Real</hi> where it is but <hi>Imaginary,</hi> to act as if it were in <hi>being,</hi> that is as far distant as the <hi>next</hi> Generation, to suspect a King in the <hi>Throne,</hi> for the fault of a King that may be yet <hi>unborn,</hi> and from a bear <hi>Possibility</hi> of Power being ill imploy'd, to Act as if it were so, is but strugling with <hi>Fan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>toms</hi> and <hi>Chimara</hi>'s, and enflaming the People with Senceless and Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditious <hi>May Be</hi>'s. A King of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> a Hundred Years hence, may be a <hi>Tyrant;</hi> must we therefore be <hi>Rude</hi> and <hi>Ʋngrateful</hi> to the King in being, whom we confess he nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther <hi>Has,</hi> and believe he never <hi>Will</hi> do us injury? It may happen in the next Generation, a King by the exercise of a <hi>Despotick Power,</hi> may deprive the Subjects of their <hi>Liberty,</hi> must we therefore <hi>Ravish</hi> the Rights of the Crown from our present <hi>Monarch,</hi> that by his Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour has regain'd, and by his Good<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness preserves them? We may be wrong'd by an <hi>Enemy,</hi> must we therefore suspect our <hi>Best Friends?</hi> and because the world must be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroied by <hi>Fire,</hi> must we run with Torches in our hands, and <hi>burn</hi> our Houses now, in dread of the <hi>General</hi> Conflagration? Surely none are so mad to grant it! and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore to strike People with Dread<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful expectations, of what may hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen we know not when, and set up <hi>Possibilities,</hi> and <hi>Contingencies</hi> to unravel and perplex <hi>present</hi> Affairs, smells Rankly of a Desig, and that our new <hi>Seditious Interpositors</hi> would enslave us, first to their <hi>Principles,</hi> and then to their <hi>Persons,</hi> as their Predecessors have once done already.</p>
            <p>Our Miseries are <hi>Endless</hi> if we stand in fear of <hi>Possibilities,</hi> for as their is nothing we <hi>Fear</hi> so certain of coming, as 'tis certain that many things we fear will <hi>never</hi> come, we should hope the best, and not by <hi>Treachery, Cowardice</hi> and <hi>Distrust</hi> of Providence, Contrive and Enlarge our own Unhappiness; for this is to <hi>Die</hi> for fear of <hi>Death,</hi> and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gulph our selves into certain Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sery, upon invented or ill ground<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed apprehensions.</p>
            <p>This Design of <hi>Amusing</hi> the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, with Evils that might happen from a <hi>Standing Army,</hi> being on Foot, how did the <hi>Mixture of In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terests,</hi> by pretending to Read his Majesties <hi>Thoughts</hi> in that affair, draw such <hi>unnatural</hi> Consequences, and Retort such Disingenious Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flections upon his suppositious fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture Conduct, as was Unsufferable in hearing, and Undutiful in Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porting; and yet how <hi>Coolely, Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dately,
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:44100:22"/>and Wisely,</hi> did His Majesty manage himself in that whole af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fair, and <hi>Silenc'd</hi> all that slaun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred his Intentions, as if he would Govern by a Standing Army: for tho possibly his Majesty might be of Opinion <hi>(as well as thousands of his Subjects of Celebrated Intelects and considerable Fortunes)</hi> that as Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like matters were then circumstan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiated, a greater <hi>Land Force</hi> was necessary than what was talk'd of; yet so great was his desire and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavour to allay the <hi>Heats,</hi> that some men were raising upon that Subject, that he suffer'd the <hi>Quiet</hi> of his People to prevail upon his <hi>Judgment,</hi> and as soon as the Bill for Disbanding the Army was Ready for the Royal Assent, he immedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ately Pass'd it, and to that great Example of <hi>Self-Denial,</hi> made the following Pathetick to the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments Speech. <hi>Feb.</hi> 1.98.
<q>
                  <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <div type="speech">
                           <opener>
                              <salute>My Lords and Gentlemen,</salute>
                           </opener>
                           <p>I came to Pass the Bill for Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>banding the Army as soon as I under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stood it was ready for Me.</p>
                           <p>Though in our present Circumstan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, there appears great hazzard in breaking such a Number of the Troops; And though I might think my self Ʋn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kindly us'd, that those Guards, who came over with me to your Assistance, and have constantly attended me in all the Actions wherein I have been engaged, should be removed from me; yet it is my fixt opinion, that nothing can be so fatal to us, as that any Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strust or Jealousie should arise between me and my People, which I must own would have been very unexpected after what I have Ʋudertaken, Ventured, and Acted for the Restoring and Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curing of their Liberties.</p>
                           <p>I have thus plainly told you the only Reason which has induced me to pass this Bill; and now I think my self oblig'd, in discharge of the Trust re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>posed in me, and for my own justifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation, that no ill consequences may lie at my Door, to tell you as plainly My Judgment, that the Nation is left too much exposed.</p>
                           <p>It is therefore incumbent upon you, to take this matter into your serious Consideration, and effectually to provide such a Strength as is necessary for the safety of the Kingdom, and the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>servation of the Peace which God hath given us.</p>
                        </div>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
               </q>
            </p>
            <p>The House of Commons in an Address were pleas'd to tell the King, that the passing the Act for Disbanding the Army, <hi>gave great satisfaction to his Majesties Subjects, and that his compliance with the Pun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tual Execution thereof, would prevent all occasion of Distrust or Jealousie betwen his Majesty and his People:</hi> And one would have thought it could not have miss'd that great End. Yet there were a Remnant at several Clubs, that reaching af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Sovereign Power, like the Bay of <hi>Biscay,</hi> are always Tumultuous, let the Wind blow where it will that were more enrag'd and distur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bed
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:44100:22"/>at his passing the Bill, than they were before on Pretences He would not: and at several Caballs (to use their own words) <hi>said the King had Cross bit them, foyl'd them at their own Weapons, had bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken their Measures, and Removed a Pretence, which they hoped would have been a lasting Subject of Complaint, and keeping up the pretended Fears of Arbitrary Government:</hi> Insomuch that a Gentleman of no small Fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gure in Publick Affairs, upon read<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing his Majesties Speech above re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cited, in great Passion Swore G. D. me, 'tis Impossible to circumvent this Gentleman, (meaning the King) He <hi>Countermines</hi> all Intrigues, and <hi>will Govern us in Despight of our Teethes.</hi> At othe Clubs some Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of the Faction raved against the Bill, because it had left <hi>Seven Thousand Cut-Throats,</hi> yet in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> whereas there ought not one <hi>Red</hi> or <hi>Blew</hi> Coat to have remained on this side of the Water. In hopes I suppose they being disgusted, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der Resentments of the slight, they would immediately transport them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves, comply with the Court at <hi>St. Germans,</hi> and assist them in the Restoration of <hi>Popery and Slavery:</hi> Or otherwise by leaving the Nation <hi>Defenceless,</hi> we might have no be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit by a <hi>Peace,</hi> that cost the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom so great an expence of Blood and Treasure: For what ever these men Pretend of the Zeal of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lishmen,</hi> in the <hi>Defence</hi> of their Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, and the no need of <hi>Swords</hi> in times of Peace; they do but <hi>Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raign</hi> their own Politicks: <hi>for that Peace which puts people out of a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition of Defence in case of a War, must expect a War;</hi> and such a State as leaves a People at the <hi>Mercy</hi> of an Enemy, is <hi>worse</hi> than a War it self, unless we could perswade our Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours, to be as Supine and Negli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent as they would have us be; for otherwise our <hi>Sloth</hi> and fanci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed <hi>Security</hi> is but an <hi>Invitation</hi> for them to <hi>Over-run us,</hi> or Cut our <hi>Throates</hi> while our <hi>Hands</hi> are ty'd behind us: The Pretence of Rely<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing solely upon our Fleet, Renders our safety as uncertain as the <hi>Wind</hi> and <hi>Weather,</hi> for if in time of War, when we had the assistance of a <hi>Neighbouring</hi> Fleet in Conjunction with our own, besides a Powerful <hi>Confederacy</hi> by Land, yet found we had enough to do, before we could bring our Enemies to any tolerable terms of Peace, it would be the greatest <hi>Folly</hi> in the world, to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend upon a Single Uncertain help, when we might be subdued before we could put our selves in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to a Posture of Resistance at home, or expect it from abroad. As weak is the pretence of relying upon our <hi>Militia,</hi> which <hi>for Ever</hi> will be no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing but a <hi>Ray</hi> and <hi>Ʋndisciplin'd</hi> Multitude, and to Trust to it, is to combat <hi>Wolves</hi> with <hi>Sheep,</hi> to let go a <hi>Real</hi> Security, and Rely up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on an <hi>Imaginary</hi> one. The Project of making the <hi>Militia</hi> serviceable on all occasions, is still in the Cloudes; and the <hi>Insuperable</hi> difficulties they meet with in producing the <hi>Miracle,</hi>
               <pb n="40" facs="tcp:44100:23"/>and the <hi>Delaies</hi> they give us in for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming the Stratagim, tempt us to think, they are at last fallen into the other Notion, <hi>viz. That Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gular and Disciplin'd Troops are far Superior to the Best and Strongest Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>litia in the world: that Experience and Discipline makes an Army service<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able, and where the security of a Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion requires a Marshal Strength, 'tis Ridiculously Impolitick, to Disband the Learned only to teach the Ignorant, and put the Government to the Toyle, and Expence, of making Officers and Soldiers, when we have them made to our hands.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>There is nothing but <hi>Contradicti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on</hi> and an inflexible humour go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verns this sort of People; for after they had lost their vain Fears of Arbitrary Government, in the <hi>Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racter</hi> they themselves give the <hi>King,</hi> they Shelter under the Danger that might rise from the <hi>Army</hi> it self; and yet after all the <hi>Rude</hi> and <hi>Ʋn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gentile</hi> Language they give both Officers, and Soldiers, yet at last the Power of <hi>Truth</hi> has forc'd them into this Ingenious confession<note n="†" place="margin">Argument a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst a Standing Army <hi>p.</hi> 30. &amp; 31.</note>
               <hi>that what they have said against Standing Armies, they would be understood of such as are In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>struments of Tyranny, and their Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries Ruin, and not of our</hi> Present Army, <hi>which was raised by consent of Parliament, in the Just and Necessa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry War; and next under God and our great and glorious Deliverer, have, by their Bravery and Conduct, preserved our Liberties and the Protestant Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligion through Europe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>There are a sort of <hi>Talkers</hi> that ought to have good Memories, and these Seditious Bablers, tho they have an <hi>Excellent</hi> faculty in the Former, they are extremely <hi>Defe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive</hi> in the Latter, for 'twas this <hi>very Army,</hi> that next to God and our great Deliverer, have by their Bravery, and Conduct, preserved our Liberties, and the Protestant Religion through <hi>Europe,</hi> that in other Places<note n="*" place="margin">Argument a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst a Standing Army. <hi>p.</hi> 29.</note> they call common <hi>Cut Throates and Murder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers</hi> by Profession, and under those <hi>Hard Names,</hi> move that there may not be<note n="†" place="margin">Answer to the Ballancing. Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter.</note>
               <hi>One Soldier</hi> left in <hi>England.</hi> 'Tis a great Shame and Pity that the Army han't the Priviledge of bringing Actions of Slander a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst the <hi>Mixture,</hi> for as every in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jur'd Person and Fraternity ought to have Reparations Proportionable to their <hi>Sufferings</hi> by Slanderous Tongues; so I am very Confident the <hi>Free-Holders</hi> of <hi>England</hi> would give them <hi>Swinging</hi> Damages, where the Agressors confess the Action. Well,</p>
            <p>Since then by their own Confession, There is no cause of Fear from the <hi>King,</hi> nor <hi>Danger</hi> from the Army, 'tis worth our further enquiry what has rais'd all this <hi>Dust</hi> to choak us with <hi>Jealousies</hi> and <hi>Suspitions,</hi> and after all the <hi>Reputation</hi> we have gain'd in <hi>War</hi> would sink us into a
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:44100:23"/>dangerous <hi>Remisness</hi> in time of Peace and upon <hi>Remote</hi> and <hi>Invented</hi> fears of danger that will probably never happen, <hi>Expose</hi> our selves to those which we must certainly look for, as soon as we have put our selves out of a Capacity of <hi>Resisting</hi> by Disbanding the whole Army, and the Reason I meet with in an <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>genious Author, viz.</hi> Because a sort of men set up for wonderful Patri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ots, grow Jealous of the Prerogative, and commence <hi>Zealots</hi> for Publick Liberty, who in the late Reigns, tho' we had not only the <hi>Justest</hi> Causes of Jealousie, but all the <hi>Cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainties</hi> of Evidence, that Arbitrary Power was <hi>Erecting;</hi> yet some of them were silent, and others that went into them with as hearty a Zeal for Arbitrariness, as they seem now to put on for Liberty, and in the late War laboured hard to lay us <hi>open</hi> to Invasion and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quest, what they could not compass during the War, are endeavouring to accomplish now, by all the Arts Imaginable, and leave no stone un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turned that may make a step to our <hi>Confusion,</hi> and their own <hi>Advancement;</hi> but this affair being determined by the <hi>King</hi> and <hi>Parliament,</hi> I shall add no more but my hearty Wishes, that there may never be an unhap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>py occasion, by the malice of our Foreign Enemies, or the Treache<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of the Mixture, to convince us by a Dear bought experience <hi>Who were in the Right.</hi> However,</p>
            <p>Tho' this Matter is at length ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>commodated, as you have heard al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready, to shew their <hi>Envy, Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tousness</hi> and <hi>Ambition</hi> is never to be satisfy'd, till themselves be in Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, or all Overturned: they re-as<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sume their never-failing Topicks, <hi>Arbitrary Officers</hi> and <hi>Mismanagements,</hi> and through the sides of his Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sters, wound his Majesty in his Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, and under the general name, and cry against the Court, reflect upon his Sacred Person, for though they don't explain it in words at length; but hide themselves under Dubious and Abiguous Terms, their meaning is as Intelligible as that its day when the Sun's upon the Meri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dian. None but the King has Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er of <hi>modelling</hi> the Court, or exchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging the Ministery, and they might as well say the King was the head Conspirator to Introduce the pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Slavery, as to say he appoints the <hi>Instruments</hi> to accomplish it: and how they will reconcile this, either with the <hi>Character</hi> they are pleased to give them, or the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>found Respect and Duty they pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to owe him, is past my Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derstanding.</p>
            <p>I am no <hi>Advocate</hi> for ill Ministers, and they that know <hi>Who</hi> are such, would do well to tell them so, or apply themselves where the Discove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry will be <hi>Welcome,</hi> and Mismanage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments redress'd, and if they don't take the Legal Method of convict<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing such Offenders, their pretences will by all that understand them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves be censured, like <hi>Sir H. D. C.
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:44100:24"/>Petition,</hi> to be <hi>Frivolous, Vaxatious,</hi> and <hi>Scandalous.</hi> I know they will answer 'tis none of their <hi>business:</hi> and I must reply, they do ill to <hi>Concern</hi> themselves with that which is not; for 'tis less every Man's Duty to <hi>Rail,</hi> than seck to <hi>Remedy</hi> what they know is <hi>Amiss:</hi> and if they know it not, they are much more to blame, to make Worthy Mens Reputati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, the Subjects of idle and envi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous <hi>Banter,</hi> unless they covet the name of <hi>Buisie-bodies,</hi> or what is worse, <hi>Common Slanderers.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>There is a <hi>Blind</hi> side, and <hi>Weak</hi> part in the Populace, that easily yields to any Assault, which all that low Sedition endeavour to secure to themselves, and that is, they natural<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly love to hear Great Men spoken ill of, and are never better pleas'd than when their Ears are drumm'd with <hi>Rancorous</hi> Discourses and Malicious Insinuations against their Superiors: which the <hi>Mixture</hi> knowing, they frequent publick places, and with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out considering their own <hi>Quality,</hi> and the Port they ought to keep, Associate with all Companies, to Exagerate the <hi>Faults</hi> and <hi>Misfortunes</hi> of the Government, which they al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways do to the height, and make every <hi>Mole hill</hi> a <hi>Mountain,</hi> every <hi>Gnat</hi> a <hi>Camel,</hi> every slip or stumble a Dangerous Symptom of approach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing <hi>Ruin,</hi> and hint them with such a superfetationed. Fears and Jealou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sies, as if the whole frame of Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture were dissolving, and the world on the Brink of Rain by the mis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>management of those they are plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed to call <hi>Ignorant</hi> and ill design<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Ministers, and then sigh out Damnation against them, with such hidious Accents, as engages their Auditors to believe and publish them, and by these little Artifices of the <hi>Mixture,</hi> false Report's are spread, and the King and Court <hi>Traduced</hi> when there is no Cause or Reason to give them Credit. Hence <hi>Ill</hi> Constructions are put up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on <hi>Ʋsefull</hi> and <hi>Innocent</hi> Actions. Ill <hi>Turns</hi> are given to <hi>Well intended</hi> de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signs, and every <hi>Trip</hi> in the Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nistration, is magnified by <hi>unjust</hi> ag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gravations, without making an Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowance for the <hi>Difficulties,</hi> under which the <hi>Ministery</hi> for many years have laboured: in maintaing a War by <hi>Sea</hi> and <hi>Land,</hi> when our Money was debased, our Credit <hi>Sunk,</hi> and almost at an Impossibility to retrieve it: besides the Care and Thought, in uniting men of <hi>different</hi> Parties, different <hi>Principles,</hi> and <hi>Different In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terests,</hi> to contribute towards the common Preservation: which no Man knows the trouble of, but those that under-went the <hi>Burden</hi> of it, which if Impartially weighed, and considered with due regard to the <hi>Circumstances</hi> of the <hi>time</hi> and <hi>neces<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sities</hi> of Affairs, it would not only cool the heat of their Enemies, but merit the <hi>Applauses</hi> and <hi>Thanks</hi> of those very Men, who are so for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward to condemn them without considering how much the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>is <hi>Isseaknect,</hi> and the Honour and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putation of it <hi>Broken,</hi> by these ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norant and ungrateful <hi>Ʋnderminers.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="43" facs="tcp:44100:24"/>
            <p> No Government on Earth is so compleatly perfect, but something will be amiss in the Administration, and some unhappy occasions of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaints will arise; but the ways by which the Seditious <hi>Intermixture</hi> manage themselves, plainly disco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver their Designs are not to <hi>Recti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fy</hi> Disorders, but to <hi>countenance</hi> their own Clamours against the King and Court, because they are not infal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble: whereas a modest and sincere Intention for the Publick Good, would first consider how far promo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting such suggestions would carry them, since if they look back but a few Pages into our History, they will find that the same complaints have already kindled a <hi>War,</hi> and many a Doleful Tragedy amongst us. 'Tis impossible to know what they mean, by what they say, for they take the measure of good and evil, not from the Nature and Ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dency of Actions, but from the Characters of Persons, and they are <hi>Elected</hi> or <hi>Reprobated,</hi> as the Persons are esteemed for, or against the Party, to which their Natural propensities, or sordid <hi>Interests</hi> incline them, and being tinged with <hi>Malice</hi> and <hi>Mal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>contentedness,</hi> they think nothing more their duty than to feed and <hi>cherish</hi> un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>natural Heats and Divisions, till they can blow up the sparks of their <hi>Fren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sie</hi> into publick <hi>Combustions.</hi> 'Tis their natural humour to dislike, and as fast as they are able subvert e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very established Government, and 'tis no wonder, for what can Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strain Mad men from railing at their Keepers, and Governours, and the Laws, which Fetters them up from those <hi>Outrages,</hi> that they are so eager to act upon their Country.</p>
            <p>There is scarce a Crime to be mentioned in reference to the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lic, but they confidently charge it upon the <hi>Ministry;</hi> but keep the Proof of them in the <hi>Clouds,</hi> as if the World were obliged to believe malicious Reports, upon the Credit or a spightful hearsay, which have neither Being nor Beginning, Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour nor Pretence to justifie them. There is all the reason in the world that <hi>Ill</hi> Ministers should be <hi>punish<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed,</hi> and he would be one of the worst of Men, that would either palliate their <hi>Fault,</hi> or protect their <hi>Persons</hi> when they are <hi>Convicted</hi> of what they stand accused; but yet there is no Reason that any man should be scandalized, and suf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer upon the <hi>Naked</hi> account of a <hi>Running</hi> Clamour, that has no o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther <hi>Father,</hi> but the malicious <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ventions</hi> of those that are strugling for their <hi>Places.</hi> It is no wonder to hear the greatest Worth Defa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med, the wisest Conduct Suspect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, the Profoundest Wisdom slight<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and Men of the most <hi>Exam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plary Vertue</hi> evil spoken of. The en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vious eyes of some Men, will for e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver be disturb'd for so great a Lustre. The <hi>Israelites</hi> envied <hi>Moses,</hi> the <hi>Jews</hi> scandaliz'd the Blessed <hi>Jesus,</hi> the <hi>Romans</hi> suffered <hi>Bellisarius</hi> to beg a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout their Streets, that had been thrice their <hi>Deliverer,</hi> and no soon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er were the <hi>Athenian</hi> Captains by
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:44100:25"/>their Excellent Conduct, Valour, and Success, rais'd in the Esteem for their very Enemies, but they were presently <hi>Envy'd, Impovrished,</hi> and <hi>Proscribed</hi> by their <hi>own</hi> Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trymen. The Renowned <hi>Caesar</hi>'s fall was owing as well to the Envy as Malice of <hi>Republican Brutus,</hi> and <hi>Cassius.</hi> 'Tis a great piece of Folly to think the worse of any Man for being <hi>Envy'd</hi> and <hi>evil</hi> spoken of; for 'tis certain the <hi>Wisest</hi> and <hi>Best</hi> Man in the Nation, though others may, shall never escape <hi>Censure;</hi> therefore heavy Accusations and Crimes of the highest Nature, ought to be well proved, before they are believed, or spread abroad to the Prejudice of great Men in their <hi>Lives, Honours, and Estates,</hi> for if it be enough to be <hi>Accused</hi> where shall we find a Man that is <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nocent.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>We have heard many unpardo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable Crimes objected against the <hi>Courut,</hi> but how rarely do we hear of any proof made against them; and therefore since the <hi>Seditious In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terpositors,</hi> after all their tedious Searches and Examinations, have not been able to descry the Dangers they pretend to fear; 'tis a suffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent Principle of Presumption, that their <hi>Jealousies</hi> are <hi>ill grounded,</hi> that they find fault meerly for the sake of finding fault, and like Boys ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving blown a <hi>Soap-Bubble</hi> from a Walnut shell, resolve to keep it up as long as they have breath to fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low it. Nay, since they exhibit <hi>foul</hi> and <hi>dismal</hi> Charges against the <hi>Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nistry,</hi> without referring to any Act of the Ministers to make it good, they prove nothing but that they are <hi>Oppressed</hi> with Envy, and ill-na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture; for they are not so <hi>Ʋnskill<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full</hi> at improving the Minutest <hi>Pec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cadillo's,</hi> that had they been furnish<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed with any shadow of Truth, they would not have smoother'd them, and therefore since they have pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duced none, the Reader may just<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly conclude they have none to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duce. And all undesigning men, not withstanding all the <hi>scare Crows</hi> that are set up to fright us, may with great satisfaction and quiet, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend upon his Majesty's Promise made to the House of Commons<note n="*" place="margin">Martis 4. die Aprilis. 1699.</note> in answer to their Address, <hi>viz. That He will take the best care he can, that all sorts of mis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>managements, and Irregularities shall be Prevented or Redress'd.</hi> So that upon the whole matter our Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies crying out against the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in <hi>general</hi> Terms, without be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing able to produce any thing worth the hearing, to justifie their Noise and Clamours; they prove nothing but their want of Breeding and bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter <hi>Arguments,</hi> and their Calumnies when driven home will recoyl up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on their own Heads; for they that charge others with Crimes they can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not prove, Indict and Convict them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves of <hi>Falsity.</hi> and as this Offence may be the Parent of many Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sturbances, so among our other <hi>Real</hi> Grievances, it calls for a timely <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dress,</hi> for its infinitely below Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity,
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:44100:25"/>to indulge, or neglect a hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mour that proceeds from nothing but Invincible Pride and Peevishness. However.</p>
            <p>Certainly Causes there are, for all these complaints are not made for nothing. There can be no <hi>Smoak</hi> but there must be some <hi>Fire;</hi> and therefore to be just to my Reader, and satisfy my <hi>Country,</hi> I must not smoother them; but in Conscience and Honesty am obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged to bring some of them upon the <hi>Stage,</hi> and shew the Reasons why there are so many complaints against the Court, and the first I encounter is,</p>
            <p>That many of the Seditious Mix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture are under great Disappoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments. <hi>They want Places</hi> of <hi>Profit</hi> that they may Repair <hi>their Tatter'd Fortunes</hi> at the Expence of the Public, and Places of <hi>Trust,</hi> that they may have it in their Power to turn the Scales, if ever the Beam should be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gin to Totter. And shew their <hi>Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quisite</hi> Parts in Doing <hi>Nothing, and Ʋndoing</hi> All Things. And the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment being supply'd at present with Able and Experienc'd States<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, and that 'tis <hi>too long</hi> to go <hi>Barefoot,</hi> till they can be Recruited with <hi>Dead mens Shooes,</hi> they would <hi>pull them off,</hi> and force a way to their Preferment, through the Reputati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons of the present <hi>Ministers,</hi> and for that End <hi>only,</hi> endeavour to make the present Ministers uneasie to themselves, and hateful to o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, that they may turn them out, and thrust themselves into their Pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces; and this Chicanery they ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nage with so much Art and Indu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stry, at their several Clubs and Eat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting-Houses, as if all were going to ruin, unless they be speedily <hi>Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pl<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>y'd,</hi> and such Methods observed to Regulate Disorders, as they on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly can propose. though when their Notions come to be Examin'd, 'tis a Thousand to one, but they are utterly Impracticable, Dangerous in the Use, and Destructive in the End; But the Vulgar not perceiv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing what's in the cover'd Dish, they run into the same <hi>Cry</hi> against the <hi>Court,</hi> and eagerly spend their mouths in the Chase, which their Leaders have started, without knowing what the Game is, how it must be dres<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed, or who must feed upon the Carcass when they have help'd to catch it.</p>
            <p>Noise and Nonsence is enough to set all the Idle <hi>Tools</hi> of the <hi>Seditious Mixture</hi> a <hi>Madding,</hi> and therefore having swallowed the Infectious Vehicle, it soon has its Opera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and now they all Applaud the Contrivances and Stratagems of these State <hi>Empericks,</hi> as the on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Physitians that can cure all the Distempers in the Publick Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nistration: the only Patriots that can heal our Breaches, and restore to every <hi>Factious</hi> and <hi>Impoverish<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed</hi> Zealot, what he has a mind to. And in order to it <hi>Railing</hi> at the Ministry, is called <hi>Liberty and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perty, and Freedom of Speech,</hi> and Des<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pising Authority, is call'd not fear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the face of Men in their <hi>Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try</hi>'s
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:44100:26"/>Cause: when their Country is no more concerned in their In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vectives and Quarrels against the Court, than they would be for their Country, if 'twere in their Power to serve it. Let these Underminers of the Ministry make what pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tences they please, self-interest is at the bottom of all their <hi>Rares-Shews</hi> for Reforming what's Amiss, and the Truth of the matter is, these Gentlemen having their Wants to Lead, and the Devil to Drive, they can find no such <hi>Expedient</hi> to supply the former, and please the latter, as by changing the Ministry, and thrusting in themselves to accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plish what they aim at; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore prosecute the design according<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly with uncommon Vigour. See them set round a Table with all their Politicks about them, affecting as Zealous a look as if every Man were a <hi>Machivel,</hi> and as expert in Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dressing Grievances, and Prevent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Abuses, as <hi>Solon,</hi> or <hi>Lycurgus,</hi> and now whatever opens their mouths against the Government, no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing but the hopes of a Place, can shut them, and that does it effectually. As a late Poet Sings.
<q>
                  <l>Attempts to purifie the Court,</l>
                  <l>Is damning men of Places:</l>
                  <l>Till decently they send them home,</l>
                  <l>And get themselves put in their Rome,</l>
                  <l>And then they'll change their Faces.</l>
                  <l>'Tis not because some In are Bad,</l>
                  <l>That form's Fears, and Preten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces;</l>
                  <l>But wants of Equipage and Post,</l>
                  <l>And supplies at the Publick Cost,</l>
                  <l>To keep Coach and Six, and Wenches.</l>
               </q>
            </p>
            <p>The most serious Discourses a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongst them, and of Weightiest Matters, at last Centre in their wants of Preferment, and begin they where they will, a <hi>Place</hi> is the end of it. And though they may smo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther their <hi>Desires</hi> and <hi>Ambitious</hi> aims a while, and appear only publick Spirited <hi>Patriots;</hi> yet their Visor at length drops off, and their de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signs are discover'd, <hi>They want an Office,</hi> a lively instance whereof I heard but the other day in a Cof<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fee-house, where a Diminutive A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nimal of a late, and from a mean Rise, tho' now arriv'd to a great Estate, being heartily railing against the <hi>Administration</hi> and sighing out his Fears for his dear Country and poor <hi>England.</hi> A <hi>Gentleman</hi> smartly Reprimands the Fop, tells him his Family was once regarded as men in the true <hi>Interest</hi> of the Nation. And tho' his Father's Chair <hi>sliding</hi> from under him, the sall had swell'd his Spleen, turn'd his Brain, and af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fected his Uncle's by Simpathy: He was sorry to see the <hi>Son</hi> al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>so discover more weakness and <hi>Ill</hi> nature in the Family, in <hi>Cursing</hi> and Reviling the Publick Manage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment and promoting discontents in
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:44100:26"/>the Nation. To whom the Up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>start replyed, <hi>I will, and ought to do it, for the Court has us'd me Barba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rousty,</hi> and the <hi>Place</hi> I was a Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>didate for they have given to ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther. In short he <hi>Over valued</hi> him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>self, by aspiring to the degree of a <hi>States man,</hi> and was <hi>angry</hi> that a <hi>fitter</hi> man had the Preserence; and now his disappointment must be call'd a <hi>National</hi> Greivance and Mis-management. And if you search to the bottom of all our <hi>Clamours</hi> still the want of a <hi>Place</hi> is the cause of them.</p>
            <p>Some of the <hi>Murmurers</hi> it's true, are modester or rather subtilter than others; yet all issue at last in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>the same thing, and tho' the Poy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son does not break out at the <hi>mouth,</hi> yet they have their Methods too, and <hi>Slander</hi> the Administration with their <hi>Ears</hi> and their <hi>Looks,</hi> and whilst others Clacks are running accent and confirm their Calum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies, by Tipping the Wink, Shrug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging the <hi>Shoulders,</hi> and shaking the <hi>Head</hi> so <hi>dismally</hi> as suggests more Crimes against the <hi>Court</hi> than the World ever knew, or Arithmetick can number. And if the Stream runs against a <hi>Minister</hi> they think their Enemy, a familiar <hi>Nod,</hi> or gratious <hi>Smile</hi> from his Lordship in <hi>Mum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mery</hi> confirms all the Slanders which are <hi>broach'd</hi> at this Cabal, and shall pass them as Confidently, as if they were Mathunatical Demonstrations, when peradventure there is not one true Syllable in all the Clatter.</p>
            <p>Others of this Seditious <hi>Mixture,</hi> make their <hi>Wants</hi> and <hi>Necessities</hi> the cause of promoting Discontents and Jealousies, and <hi>Raffle</hi> for <hi>Prefer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> and <hi>Places,</hi> for the same Reasons that wise men think should utterly debar them; for Hungry men ought not to be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vited to scanty Commons, their <hi>Debauched Extravagant</hi> and vain ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pences, having consumed their own <hi>Estates,</hi> there's no reason to <hi>Trust</hi> them with the Publick <hi>Purse,</hi> or Offices that may give them an op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunity of <hi>Oppressing</hi> the Subject to supply their <hi>Necessities,</hi> and length<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>en their own <hi>Teathers</hi> by defraud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing other men of their Right of Common. I am not unsensible that it is thought a great piece of <hi>Poli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy</hi> in a Prince, to make frequent changes in his <hi>Court,</hi> and when some have sill'd their Pockets, to give them leisure to spend it; and oblige others of his Subjects with the like <hi>Advantages.</hi> I will not dispute whither this may prove advantagious to the <hi>Crown;</hi> but am of Opinion 'tis detremental to the <hi>Subject,</hi> for the same Reason that<note n="†" place="margin">Epitomy of <hi>J<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>sephus.</hi> p. 488.</note>
               <hi>Tiberius</hi> gave to his Friend up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on asking him that que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stion: I seldom, says he change my Governours of Provinces be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cause every new hungry Comer, racks the People by new <hi>Exactions,</hi> till they have fill'd their Coffers, and then are at quiet. And to this purpose told them, that a poor <hi>La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zar</hi> having his sores covered with
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:44100:27"/>
               <hi>Flies,</hi> which he endeavour'd not to drive away from feeding on his <hi>Flesh,</hi> the Spectators believing it proceeded from his inability to do it, they went near to do that Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice for him; but he pray'd them to-let the <hi>Flies</hi> alone, for having now glutted themselves with my <hi>Blood</hi> saith he, they don't suck so <hi>Greedily,</hi> but that I enjoy a little ease; but if you drive them away, <hi>fresh</hi> flies will light upon my <hi>Sores</hi> and suck me to <hi>Death.</hi> Which ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plyed to <hi>Beggarly</hi> Pretenders for <hi>Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployments,</hi> puts a <hi>Bar</hi> to their Impor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunate <hi>Solicitations</hi> especially when they take such <hi>Indirect</hi> courses to obtain what they seek for. Mens Necessities may be great, but good mens <hi>Loyalty</hi> will surmount their <hi>Wants</hi> and not put them upon <hi>rob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bing</hi> the King of his Poeples Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Affections, to fill their own <hi>Bellies;</hi> but rather to suffer any thing for his Majesty than cause him in the least to suffer by or for them. They have a great deal to answer for, who by the <hi>State-Craft</hi> of pressing for Redress of Grei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vances, would amend their own Circumstances, by raising <hi>Hurrica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>no</hi>'s in the State, and stirring up such <hi>Commotions</hi> as sometimes shat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Constitution, and as our own <hi>Memoirs</hi> can too sadly inform us, often intirely Deface and Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn it. When these dangerous In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cendiaries first set out to Awe the <hi>Government,</hi> what pains do they take to shew themselves disaffected, and hope to get <hi>Places</hi> by Argu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of their Disloyalty, and run against the <hi>Court</hi> in hopes they will ask their <hi>Price,</hi> and take them off, by bestowing <hi>Preferments</hi> upon them. For those Methods being succcess<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful in former <hi>Reigns,</hi> they revive them in this,
<q>
                  <l>King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second knew their Game,</l>
                  <l>And Places gave and <hi>Pensions;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And had King <hi>William</hi>'s <hi>Money</hi> flown,</l>
                  <l>His Majesty would soon have known</l>
                  <l>Their <hi>Consciences</hi> Dimenssons,</l>
                  <l>But he has <hi>Wisely</hi> given them up,</l>
                  <l>To work their own <hi>Desires;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And laying <hi>Arguments</hi> aside,</l>
                  <l>As things which have in <hi>vain</hi> been try'd,</l>
                  <l>To <hi>Fastings, Want,</hi> and <hi>Prayers.</hi>
                  </l>
               </q>
            </p>
            <p>'Tis a Lewd and Unwarrantable step in <hi>Politicks,</hi> for Seditious <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termedlers</hi> to expect to be Gratified by <hi>Profitable Employments,</hi> for being intolerably <hi>Vexatious</hi> to the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment; and by all the shark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Ways and Means imaginable, to place themselves at the <hi>Helm;</hi> for this <hi>Cunning</hi> is not always Crown'd with <hi>Success;</hi> but often<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times the <hi>wild</hi> pursuers draw down <hi>Ruinous</hi> Consequences on their own Heads, by attempting to <hi>Rise</hi> by such <hi>Natorious</hi> Acts as call their <hi>Fidelities</hi> into Question, for if men can be Loyal no longer than they and <hi>bribed</hi> to their Duties by Prefer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, the King leans on <hi>Broken
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:44100:27"/>Reedes,</hi> and cannot be <hi>Secure</hi> till he has as many Good <hi>Places</hi> in his Gift, as he has <hi>Bad</hi> and <hi>Hungary</hi> Subjects in his Kingdom, and if men would but consider that they have to do with a <hi>Prince,</hi> that is not to be <hi>Hector'd</hi> out of his Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vours; they would give over throw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing <hi>Obsticles</hi> in the way of their own <hi>Rising,</hi> seeing their is no great <hi>Feats</hi> to be done in this <hi>Reign</hi> by such a Fantastical Conduct: whereas the Exercise of <hi>Humility, Loyalty</hi> and <hi>Modesty</hi> would melt his <hi>Heroick</hi> Soul, into such Gracious <hi>Considera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions,</hi> as would put him upon con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sidering how he might be still <hi>more</hi> Beneficial to his People.</p>
            <p>The Reigning <hi>Sins, Pride, Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bition, and Atheism,</hi> are other Grei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vancies that call aloud for <hi>Redress,</hi> and the neglect of <hi>Suppressing</hi> them; are to be reckon'd among our Real Mis-managements, and as the Cause of the Molestations they afflict the State. Envy and Obloquy, spares no body, the most unblemish'd Vertue is not sheilded from their <hi>Darts.</hi> 'Tis Defined by <hi>Cicero,</hi> to be <hi>Grief</hi> conceived in the Mind, at the <hi>Good</hi> which another man <hi>enjoies;</hi> and that good Especially, by which the Envious Man receives no <hi>inju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry;</hi> but they are <hi>Sick</hi> because other Men are <hi>Well,</hi> and the better it is with <hi>Another</hi> the worse it is with <hi>him.</hi> When Men have consu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med their own <hi>Estates</hi> by Idle, and Extavagant <hi>Expences,</hi> they en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy those that are grown <hi>Rich</hi> by their <hi>Industry;</hi> and this makes them <hi>Curious</hi> in Enquiring, and <hi>Prying</hi> into other Mens affairs that they may find something to <hi>Lessen</hi> them. A Temper so far from being <hi>Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stian,</hi> that there's nothing of <hi>Humi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity</hi> but much of the <hi>Devil</hi> in it. Hence it is that the Ratling of a Courtiers <hi>Coach</hi> frights them out of their <hi>Sences,</hi> the sight of a fine <hi>Coate,</hi> makes 'em ready to tear their own <hi>Clothes</hi> tho Gayer, and puts them into such a Heate, that nothing but the Promise of a good <hi>Place</hi> can cool their Envy, or Divert them from De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claiming against the <hi>Court,</hi> telling Stories of <hi>Mis-management,</hi> Detracting from their <hi>Merits,</hi> and making large <hi>Additions</hi> to their faillings; and if the Court oblige them with some fine thing to play withal, their pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed <hi>Consciencious</hi> Clamours will sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit to their <hi>Interests,</hi> and then the Court is the Honestest place in <hi>Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stendom.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Pride</hi> and <hi>Vanity,</hi> are other In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gredients that contribute toward the composition of a <hi>Male Content;</hi> for they swell the <hi>Factions</hi> with such good opinions of <hi>Themselves,</hi> and their <hi>Capacities</hi> for Publick <hi>Employ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments,</hi> that there is a necessity for others to be Turn'd <hi>Out,</hi> that they may have an <hi>Opportunity,</hi> to shew their <hi>Rare</hi> Qualifications: and then the most compendious ways to ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain their wishes, are to calumniate the <hi>Court,</hi> and cut down the <hi>Oakes</hi> that the <hi>Shrubs</hi> and Under-wood may flourish; when all is but a grand mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stake, for neither have the <hi>Possessors</hi> deserved a Writ of Ease, nor is the
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:44100:28"/>
               <hi>Intruder</hi> qualified either with <hi>Brain</hi> or <hi>Body</hi> for it; but his Pride and Vanity screw'd up hisow <hi>Price,</hi> and represented him of greater <hi>Value</hi> than he was. But some lucky hand being so kind, to Plum the depth of his <hi>Ʋnderstanding,</hi> procur'd his <hi>Dismission,</hi> and now in Revenge, <hi>King, Church, Court, City, Country,</hi> must go to <hi>Wrack,</hi> and suffer all the Reproaches that the <hi>Wit</hi> and <hi>Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lice</hi> of the Party can Invent.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Haughty</hi> and <hi>Ambitious</hi> Antimo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>narchists, are the other Causes of all the Fears and Suspicions that are rais'd in <hi>England;</hi> for such <hi>Elevating</hi> their minds above their <hi>Ranks,</hi> and the end of their <hi>Institution,</hi> and wearing <hi>Venerable</hi> Titles; to humor Anbitious <hi>Freakes</hi> some <hi>Popular</hi> Mag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>got, or Invented <hi>Danger</hi> to with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>draw Subjects from their Allegiance is started and therefore if we would not be chous'd out of our Legal <hi>Settlemen;</hi> before we imbibe their <hi>Delusions,</hi> we had need make sharp <hi>Enquiries,</hi> whether the Specious pretences of their <hi>Reformers,</hi> don't design to justle out that Univer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sal <hi>Repose,</hi> which we have en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyed under his Majesties Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and therefore are all equally oblig'd to <hi>Promote</hi> it. Innovations, which self Intrested Men would In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>troduce into the <hi>Administration</hi> of the Kingdom, have sometimes un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hing dour Regular <hi>Constitution;</hi> but we rarely hear that they have ever Corroborated the Old, or have enlar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged the Power of the Kingdom or the advantages of the People. History swells with Examples which <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firm</hi> this Truth. How Unanimous<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly have our Laws sentenc'd all <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>motions,</hi> tho Gilded with the sairest. Colours that Art could Invent 'Tis attested by the Experience of of all Ages, that the horrible Evils which Factious <hi>Innovators,</hi> by rais<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Fears and Jealousies have brought in amongst us, have been a greater burden tous than any other afflicti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on that could have happen'd. This is and ever will be the necessary concequence of such Indeavours; for if every Sorry Pretender of <hi>Grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vances,</hi> should take a Licence to Disobey his Superiors, whensoever he has a mind to deliver himself of a Complaint: then <hi>Farewell</hi> Society, for no form of Government can <hi>Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sist</hi> on these Extravagant terms, since every one <hi>Hurri'd</hi> by his <hi>Passions,</hi> would never want Plausible Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons to ground his <hi>Plea</hi> of Resisting Authority upon, and by this means our Miseries would be endless.</p>
            <p>Our Laws enjoyn us to Obey the Kingas <hi>Supreme Head</hi> and Governour, and forbid us entiring into any <hi>en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gagements,</hi> that by the widest Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>structions may seem to clash with our <hi>Duty.</hi> Now such as by an Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plicit Surrender, devote themselves to any Person or Embodied Society, which are Superior to them; if that Society have given any signs of <hi>Disloyalty,</hi> or of Advancing them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves, the People are in great Dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger of being stript of their <hi>fidelity</hi> to their <hi>Leige Lord,</hi> when their <hi>Leaders</hi> who ought to annimate the
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:44100:28"/>Allegiance of the Lower Orders of Men; become themselves the first <hi>Desertors.</hi> 'Tis enough we give Men of <hi>Quality</hi> the Respect that is Due to them, without being so much their <hi>Vassals</hi> as to sell that Liberty of ours, of which the King is the only Master of. Not that I blame a Deference paid to great Men, but I would not have their <hi>Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tative</hi> Influence, Hand over Head betray us to comply with their <hi>Criminal</hi> Passions; 'tis worth the while therefore first to observe as I said before, whether these Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formers of <hi>Abuses</hi> themselves are <hi>Loyal</hi> and <hi>Steady</hi> in the <hi>Interest</hi> of their Sovereign, and whither there is not a Snake hidden in the Grass: and that under pretence of recti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fying <hi>Disorders</hi> and <hi>Mis-manage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments,</hi> they have not a Crafty De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sign to Hook us into a <hi>Combinati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on</hi> that Undermines the Throne of our <hi>Prince,</hi> for if we get any Light, that they Drive at so <hi>Black</hi> an At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt, we must disdainfully Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treat from such <hi>Perfidious</hi> Designs, and Generously sacrifice every Glit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering Advantage which they have cajol'd us with, to our Duty. And whatsoever Interest starts up, to cleave Inviolably to the King; for as his Side is the Justest, so the Advantages of Sticking to it, well be the most Honourable and Satis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factory.</p>
            <p>'Tis only the effect of a Giddy presumption, that <hi>Spirits</hi> on tumul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuous Subjects, to <hi>Quarrel</hi> with the Administration of the State, ima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gining that publick Affairs would Roll more Smoothly, if themselves were in the <hi>Ministry,</hi> or things were managed by their fanciful <hi>Schemes,</hi> whereas 'tis their Duty to submit to the Laws, to banish Murmuring, and stifle Opposition, when a Conformity to their Regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lations are required. But if Abu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ses does insinuate into the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, no doubt but we ought to wish they were Reformed, but let no Men undertake it, without a <hi>Lawful</hi> Commission, and certain Evidence of the Facts: For all ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trajudicial attempts, and <hi>Sinister</hi> Ends, tend rather to the Shaking of the <hi>Monarchy</hi> than Amending its Defects. And after all that State menders pretend to in changing the Ministry, the King is the proper Judge of every Alteration; and tho He should not Agree to such De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands, as carry a fair Plaufibility of Right for their being Granted, still ought to <hi>Acquiesce</hi> with Confidence, that his <hi>Non-concurrence</hi> is for the Real good of his Subjects; and tho the Reasons are behind the <hi>Cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain</hi> to us, they are Evident and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monstrative to <hi>Himself</hi> and Council. How happy are we then, that have a King that Caresses his Subjects as his <hi>Children,</hi> and with an Indifatiga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Application Propagates the Wel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fare of all under his Charge? How How Dutiful and Diligent there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore should all his Subjects be in their several Stations, who Bask un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der that Sun-shine, to smother the Gusts and Ill Designs of the Mix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:44100:29"/>
               <hi>Early,</hi> before they become Gloomy Clouds, big with impend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ruin to darkin the Lustre of Roy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Grace.</p>
            <p>Here I had the thoughts of Easing my Reader from the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tigue I have given him; but I find my self under a necessity of trailing him a little further, before I can dismiss him with intire satisfaction. For having shewed him that there is a design carrying on at several <hi>Cabals,</hi> either utterly to deprive his Majesty, or at least to lessen his Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority, I must shew him now, that since it could not be done at once as in the <hi>Assassination Plot,</hi> they are now doing it by <hi>Degrees,</hi> and as the <hi>Wolves</hi> would first rob the <hi>Sheep</hi> of the assistance of their faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full Allies, that they might become an easie prey to their <hi>Devourers;</hi> so that that the <hi>Mixture</hi> might <hi>Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pose</hi> upon the King at pleasure, 'twas resolved at another <hi>Club,</hi> and Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lished by one of their <hi>Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>critaries</hi> in a Pamphlet<note n="†" place="margin">Page 7.</note> call'd, <hi>An Answer to the Ballancing Letter,</hi> That</p>
            <p>
               <hi>To preserve the Honour of the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment: none, or few, who have gain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Offices, should be Members of the House of Commons,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Sure the Gentlemen of this <hi>Club</hi> are Men of great <hi>Interest</hi> and <hi>Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>respondence,</hi> and what they transack in their Club Room, strangely <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fluences</hi> other Places; for there is scarce a <hi>Page</hi> in the whole <hi>L<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>bel</hi> that has not been the Subject of <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bates</hi> and <hi>Resolutions</hi> in more Emi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent <hi>Ascociations,</hi> and then no won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der to see things go at this Rate, and themselves so mightily concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for the <hi>Honour of the Nation,</hi> which was never further in their thoughts, than to make what <hi>earn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings</hi> they could, from their preten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of having served the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment: for some are well known a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongst them, that now rail at all above and below them, that are not of their Faction, that have had their <hi>Hands</hi> deeper in the King's <hi>Pockets,</hi> and have received larger shares of his Bounty, than any men of their Quality in <hi>England;</hi> and yet are so <hi>Ʋngrateful,</hi> that they ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver afford his Majesty one good word: but upon all Occasions de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tract from his <hi>Virtues,</hi> Eclipse his <hi>Glory,</hi> and by all the Power they have <hi>lessen</hi> his Authority; and in this their <hi>Favourite</hi> Project aim at nothing less than if it were <hi>possible</hi> to leave him <hi>Friendless</hi> also, for un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der that name they would exclude his Officers; which are but the <hi>late Kings</hi> Politicks Revers'd, and tend no other purpose but to express their <hi>Ingratitude.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Every <hi>Protestant</hi> Getleman in <hi>England,</hi> under such requisite Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lifications as the Law has establish<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, have a right to be Elected <hi>Members</hi> of <hi>Parliament,</hi> and nothing can look with a more <hi>Arbitrary</hi> Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenance upon the <hi>Gentry</hi> of <hi>England,</hi> than a design of this Nature; for it takes away their <hi>Birth rights,</hi> and sinks their Honour in the Esteem of the Nation, as it distinguishes them
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:44100:29"/>as men <hi>Ʋnfit</hi> to serve their Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, because they have the Honour of serving their King. Is this for <hi>the Honour of the Gouernment,</hi> to perswade the World, that they that serve the King are not to be <hi>trust<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed</hi> in the management of <hi>Publick</hi> Affairs. What a manifest Contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diction is this to common Sence, that those which other whiles they call <hi>the King</hi>'s <hi>Friends,</hi> must have a mark set upon them as his greatest <hi>Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies:</hi> for if they truly love and faithfully serve the King, <hi>as I am inclined to think they do, because the Mixture hate them,</hi> they will offer no nothing, but what they appre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hend will be of service both to <hi>King</hi> and <hi>Couutry,</hi> whose <hi>Iuterests</hi> can never be divided, but <hi>Live</hi> and <hi>Die</hi> together. To think to serve the King by <hi>Injuring</hi> the Country, is to Discrown their Master and to think to <hi>oblige</hi> the Nation, by <hi>Les<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fening</hi> the Kings Authority, and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pairing his Revenue, is to Behead the people, their Interests as I said before are so Interwoven together that one cannot <hi>suffer,</hi> but the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther sensibly <hi>feels</hi> it; and therefore the <hi>Mixture</hi> ought to give the Officers some other name, or let them keep their Places. Besides, is it for <hi>the Honour of the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> to Disfranchize the Electors, and ridicule them as ignorant Ani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mals, who don't know who are fit to be their <hi>Representatives</hi> in Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. Is not this Arraigning the <hi>Commons</hi> to think an <hi>Office</hi> can <hi>cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt</hi> them, and <hi>byass</hi> them from their Duty to their <hi>Country?</hi> What Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingenious reflections are these upon <hi>Gentlemen,</hi> and what <hi>Heart Burnings</hi> will it beget among us? How do they know which way these <hi>Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers</hi> will Vote, since some Officers Vote as constantly against what they call the <hi>Court Party,</hi> as if they held their Places by no other Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nure; Ought not every Member to <hi>Vote</hi> as his Judgment directs him, without being <hi>Censured</hi> at e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very Drunken Club for so doing. And why should the <hi>Yea's</hi> be thought less <hi>Judicious</hi> and <hi>Consciencious</hi> than the <hi>No's,</hi> or the <hi>No's</hi> than the <hi>Yea's,</hi> God forbid; for these are but <hi>Bones</hi> of Dissention thrown among us to set all at squabbling: and that the <hi>Seditious</hi> may find their own account in fastning Crimes on Men of <hi>Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour</hi> and <hi>Worth,</hi> they neither know why, nor wherefore: whose <hi>Jug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings</hi> may prove of Dangerous Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sequence to the <hi>State,</hi> and to those who are <hi>Over reach'd</hi> by them.</p>
            <p>The Design they manage, in en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavouring to <hi>Exclude</hi> all that have <hi>Offices</hi> under the King out of the House of Commons is plain enough; they are afraid <hi>the Kings and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries Affairs should thrive too well,</hi> and therefore would have the House of Commons to be <hi>like themselues, all of a Piece,</hi> and wholly against the <hi>King</hi> and <hi>Court.</hi> I cannot but won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der how they dare make such <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flections</hi> upon the House of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons, as to <hi>Insinnuate</hi> there are any Parties and Factions among them, by pretending to distinguish who
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:44100:30"/>are <hi>For</hi> and <hi>Against</hi> the Interest of the King. What a Liberty of Censuring all the rest do they fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nish Conversation with? When they propose the <hi>Turning</hi> out some par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular Member, under the <hi>suppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sition</hi> that they are in the Roy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Interest, which is <hi>Ʋnkind</hi> to the <hi>Parliament,</hi> and <hi>Ʋngrateful</hi> to the <hi>King:</hi> and I am only sorry that I am not wholly at Liberty to pursue, and improve the Results of my own thoughts upon that Subject: Tho' they have partly spa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red me the labour in contriving their <hi>Schemes</hi> so <hi>Ill,</hi> that they are neither Adapted to perswade the <hi>Wise,</hi> nor to deceive the <hi>Simple,</hi> their <hi>Intrigves,</hi> and the <hi>Slanders</hi> by which they manage them, being so <hi>Open</hi> and <hi>Barefac'd,</hi> that had an Enemy De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signed to expose their <hi>Wickedness,</hi> he could not have Father'd upon them more <hi>unlucky</hi> Instances, than what is <hi>covered</hi> under this <hi>Old Trick of Secluding Members,</hi> which we hope the <hi>Lord's</hi> Wisdom and Goodness will prevent, lest the same <hi>Club</hi> when their designs are <hi>Ripe,</hi> should think their <hi>Lordships</hi> also <hi>dangerous and useless,</hi> and propose it as a Grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance to be Redress'd. <hi>For what has been done may be done again, and the same cause will produce the same effects</hi> to the end of the Chapter.</p>
            <p>Which is as evident as Demon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stration can make it, by the next step the <hi>Mixture</hi> took at a <hi>Cabal</hi> held, as I take it, at <hi>the Old Devil of St. Duustan</hi>'s, where to Express their <hi>Ingratitude</hi> to the <hi>Height,</hi> and shew what sort of <hi>Cards</hi> were <hi>Trumps,</hi> when their <hi>Spies</hi> and <hi>Emissaries,</hi> and the <hi>Agents</hi> and <hi>Factors</hi> which they keep in all corners of the Town, to Fetch and Carry, to Traffick for <hi>News,</hi> and support the Trade of <hi>Promoting Fears and Jealousies,</hi> had brought in their straggling <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ports,</hi> they came to these unkind <hi>Reso<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lutions,</hi> and order'd them to be <hi>Engross'd,</hi> and<note n="†" place="margin">Pamphlet predict. P. 22. and 13.</note>
               <hi>Printed</hi> and <hi>Published</hi> by their former <hi>Secretary,</hi> viz.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>That letting in Aliens, dimi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nishes the strength of the Nation, and therefore the</hi> Dutch <hi>must be amoved out of the Kingdom, and a Fatal day set for their departure.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Without doubt the Mixture will say these Proceedings are for the <hi>Honour of the Government too?</hi> To Invite Strangers to our Assistance, and when they have done our Work, and contributed to the Nations De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liverance from Tyranny, and Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pression; then to Treat them with Unkindness and Ingratitude; which as our case stands in expectation of what may happen, is as Opposite to the Honour and Interest of <hi>England,</hi> as Light is from Dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness.
<q>
                  <l>Tho' I've no <hi>Lilly</hi> in my belly,</l>
                  <l>This home-spun truth I'll boldly tell ye,</l>
                  <l>(And may I be no Prophet)</l>
                  <l>If thus we serve our truest Friends,</l>
                  <l>Some nameless Sparks may have their Ends:</l>
                  <l>And mischeif may come of it.</l>
                  <pb n="55" facs="tcp:44100:30"/>
                  <l> Nay those stanch Senators I doubt</l>
                  <l>Who with a Vote <hi>French</hi> Armies rout and quarrel who shall win most,</l>
                  <l>Shou'd <hi>Monsieur</hi> Land, wou'd surely fly,</l>
                  <l>And turning tail, Heroic cry,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>The Devil take the hind'most.</hi>
                  </l>
               </q>
            </p>
            <p>Certainly the Gentlemen of this <hi>Cabal</hi> are very loose in their Sen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>timents, that find those Aliens, now so great an Eye-sore, that not long since they Caressed with the highest Expressions of <hi>Respect,</hi> and made such acknowledgments of <hi>Obligations</hi> to them, that they were never able to <hi>Recompence.</hi> Pray Gentlemen what have they done to <hi>Merit</hi> your displeasure? wherein have they mis-behaved themselves to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards you, that all of a sudden they must be Ship'd off, as a Dangerous People? How long have you been perswaded that they have <hi>Dimished</hi> the strength of <hi>England,</hi> were you of this <hi>Opinion</hi> when they Landed in <hi>Torbay,</hi> and with their <hi>Swords</hi> in their hands, asserted your <hi>Liberties?</hi> Could you have done the Nations work without them? If you could why did you so earnestly request their <hi>Assistance,</hi> and if you could not, why would you have them used so <hi>unkind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly.</hi> For shame give over Affronting the <hi>Honour</hi> of <hi>English</hi> men, with such ungrateful <hi>Characters</hi> and making the Nation <hi>Contemptible</hi> in the Eyes of all the World, for the sake of a few <hi>Male-contented Clubbers,</hi> and the next time you employ your <hi>Secretaries</hi> Pens, let it be to better purpose, and enjoyn them for the Honour of your <hi>Club Room</hi> to Apologize for the <hi>slurs</hi> they have put upon the Nation al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready.</p>
            <p>But the Decree of the <hi>Cnbal</hi> you see is <hi>peremptory.</hi> Our <hi>Dutch friends</hi> must march off, and the Reason they give for it is a doughty one, <hi>viz</hi>
               <note n="†" place="margin">Lib. &amp; p. predict.</note>
               <hi>For every Foreigner living in</hi> England, say they, we <hi>have an</hi> Englishman <hi>the less.</hi> That's strange! since if we had not had their <hi>Assistance,</hi> our <hi>Quota</hi> during the War, must have been greater, and conse<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently more <hi>Englishmen</hi> must have fallen a Sacrifice to <hi>Popery</hi> and Sla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very, then has done, and therefore we have more <hi>Englishmen</hi> left alive for having had their Assistance, than in all probability we could have had, if we had wanted them; but this <hi>Core</hi> against the <hi>Dutch</hi> lies deep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er than every man's aware of; for these very men that propos'd pack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>icking off the <hi>Dutch,</hi> not long since were as zealous for promoting a Bill of Naturalization for all the <hi>French:</hi> though the latter Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on are our known <hi>Enemies,</hi> and the <hi>Dutch</hi> our faithful <hi>Allies,</hi> and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bark'd in the same Cause against them. But it seems the <hi>Mixture</hi> knew what Monarch protected the Abdicated King, whose Restorati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on is a great point among them, tho kept behind the Curtain; and where the Court of <hi>St. Germans</hi> stood; and therefore were com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pounding with the two Courts, by shewing Kindness to that Nation, and sending away the <hi>Duch,</hi> who by Inter est as Well as Alliance,
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:44100:31"/>were obliged to assist us when occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion serve'd against them both. I could urge a great deal more upon this Head, but I know they are up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the <hi>Fret</hi> already, for being touc'd in the Gall'd place, and being un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>willing to <hi>Sour</hi> 'em more, or med<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dle with a Wasps-Nest, I won't at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt to put a Statue of Brass out of Countenance, or hope to Convince or <hi>Silence</hi> Men of their Complexions.</p>
            <p>The Great Reason why the <hi>Dutch</hi> must Troop off, is still to come, and tho they were always accounted as his Majesties <hi>Domestik Servants,</hi> and have for many years attended his Royal Person in his Progresses, yet not a Hoof must be left behind: and to enforce this proposal they draw their unanswera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Argument from a Hen-Roost Metaphor, and say<note n="*" place="margin">Pag. 23.</note>
               <hi>Strangers are the nest-Eggs of a Foreign In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vasion.</hi> See how these <hi>Witty</hi> Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen tumble in their Pretty <hi>Tropes; Rickety Heads, and Arbitrary Power, Obedient Subjects and Puppy-Dogs, Invasions and Nest-Eggs. Tipical, To<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pical, Tropical, my Ped is Green.</hi> What pleasant sport might a Man make with the Grave Speeches that have been made upon these Heads, but I have no time to loose in Win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nowing <hi>chaff,</hi> or catching <hi>Butterflies:</hi> and therefore shall proceed to shew how these Gentlemen <hi>forget</hi> them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves, and <hi>Say</hi> and <hi>Ʋnsay</hi> to uphold the great <hi>Hypothesis</hi> of being perfect Enemies to his Majesty. When a Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bability of trouble from <hi>France,</hi> was <gap reason="illegible: page cropped" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>'d as a reason to keep up such a Number of Troops, as might secure the Nation fro such attempts. Than the <hi>Mixture</hi> scoffed such obviating Dangers as ridiculous Imaginations. Then we hear of nothing but the great <hi>Courage, Zeal, Fidelity, and Ʋn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>animosity of the</hi> English <hi>Nation</hi> in case of a <hi>French</hi> Invasion; but when the talk was hot about the <hi>Dutch</hi> staying or going, all those Glotious <hi>Epithets</hi> are shrunk into <hi>Meanest of Spirit,</hi> and they shew the Nation in such a <hi>Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiardly</hi> Posture, as if they stood all <hi>Shivering</hi> behend the Door, for fear of—thousand <hi>Dutchmen:</hi> or that every one of those <hi>Nest-Eggs</hi> should hatch such a Brood of <hi>Shake-Bags</hi> as would Beat all the <hi>fighting Cocks</hi> in <hi>England.</hi> Thus are we represented as <hi>Stout</hi> as <hi>Lyons,</hi> or as <hi>Fearful</hi> as <hi>Hares,</hi> as will best agree with the Designs of the <hi>Mixture:</hi> If the King would have have a Land Force, proportionable to those of our Enemies. Then there were no need of any other <hi>Guards</hi> than his <hi>Hal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berteers;</hi> for in case of any <hi>Invasion</hi> every Individual Man in <hi>England</hi> would be a <hi>Soldier;</hi> but if it be thought <hi>Reasonable, Civil and Oblig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,</hi> that the <hi>Dutch Guards</hi> should Remain in <hi>England.</hi> Then upstarts <hi>Fears</hi> and <hi>Jealousies,</hi> and remon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strate such dismal accidents may follow such an act of Gratitude, as may subject us to a Conquest and make us all <hi>Slwoes</hi> to <hi>Holland.</hi> Did ever Men make such <hi>Wretched</hi> Pretences? 'Tis a sad Symptom that ill designs are <hi>Brewing,</hi> when such <hi>Positive</hi> People are driven to such Sceptical and Doubtful <hi>Innuendo</hi>'s
<pb n="65" facs="tcp:44100:31"/>and are forc'd to take Sanctuary in Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked <hi>May Be</hi>'s, and Thwart and Affront His Majesty upon every <hi>Triffling</hi> Sug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gestion, arising from Principles of Disloy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty; so that nothing must be done for him, out of <hi>Respect</hi> to his <hi>Person,</hi> or the mighty deliverance he <hi>Acheived,</hi> till all demands of the Cabals, how unreason<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able soever, shall first be fully satisfied. But why should we wonder, 'tis natural for this mixture to be displeas'd with the <hi>Grandure</hi> and <hi>Prosperity</hi> of the <hi>Court.</hi> The height of the Kings felicity, frets their Pround and Envious Minds; and they are never so apt to spy <hi>Dangers,</hi> and complain of the badness of the <hi>Times,</hi> as when the Government is like to be most flourishing. They are incurable Male-contents, and in Dread of an Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>britrary Power, which they say, <hi>They have no Reason to suspect;</hi> yet are making <hi>Encroachments</hi> upon the Royal <hi>Authority,</hi> and lying at <hi>Catch</hi> for all advantages, and Husbanding all Opportunities, to <hi>Abate</hi> the Sovereign Prerogative; and to keep the Monarchy low, by <hi>Removing</hi> his Friends, <hi>Empoverishing</hi> his Revenue, and being imperious and inexorable in their Impositions; as may be easily Read in their Resolve to expel the <hi>Dutch,</hi>
               <note n="*" place="margin">Pamphl. praedict page. <hi>23.</hi>
               </note>
               <hi>viz. That a Fatal day be set for their Departure.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And Why a <hi>Fatal</hi> Day! they could not mean it to the <hi>Dutch Guards,</hi> for they were but going home, from whence they came to our Succour; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore must mean it in respect of us, that 'twould <hi>be fatal when we want Friends, to be refused their Assistance.</hi> They were pleas'd to call the <hi>Dutch, a dead weight upon the Nation,</hi> and I wish all others that are so, had bore them Company; and then as we have fewer <hi>Enemies,</hi> by being well Rid of the <hi>latter,</hi> and so the Balance wou'd be equal. The Libel has yet some Fragments of History, to give it a greater Currency among the Sedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tious Intermedlers; but being <hi>Nothing</hi> to their purpose, I shall not reckon it so much to mine, as to Answer them; for since my whole design was only to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pose these Leud Scriblers, I hope I have done it to your Content; and this Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fair being now <hi>Amicably</hi> Determin'd by the King and his Parliaments; nothing more ought to be added, but what I shall ever contend for, <hi>viz.</hi> a Dutiful Obedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence to our Superiors.</p>
            <p>I have now shew'd you the <hi>Reigning</hi> Evils of our present Times; give me leave to acquaint you, by what <hi>Ways and Means</hi> they are rais'd, and continued to breed Disturbances, and then I shall Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miss my Reader.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Spring</hi> and <hi>Progress</hi> of all our Causeless Fears and Jealousies, and the unhappy Consequences that have attend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Them, are owing to the more than ordinary <hi>Industry,</hi> of Seditious Men's Trafficking for <hi>News;</hi> and Employing a sort of Idle <hi>Pedling</hi> People, to Range up and down in quest of fresh Intelligence, who importune all they meet, to contri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bute to the <hi>Stock</hi> of Slaundering the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment; and if they chance to meet any of their <hi>Associates,</hi> upon the Fron<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiers of their Respective Walks, they frankly impart what they have gain'd to each other, as Beggars do their Frag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments: And seditious <hi>Clubs</hi> are the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon places of Rendevous, where they all Unload, and every particular <hi>Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber</hi> partakes of the <hi>Joint</hi> Collectons of the whole Society, where a sullen Gran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dee of the <hi>Mixture,</hi> will give a Guinea for a Tale, that humors his Designs, that will not part with half a Crown to pay a just Debt; and by this means all <hi>Reports</hi> fly abroad with such winged speed, as may <hi>Flush</hi> the Party to blazon them in all Quarters of the Town, and Country. And if they get a <hi>Story</hi> by the end, That
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:44100:32"/>looks a little <hi>a Squint</hi> upon the Court, and yet is not in it self full enough of Remark and Wonder: The <hi>Club Vamps</hi> it with New Circumstances of their own, <hi>Alter, Improve,</hi> and <hi>Refine</hi> it, till they have made it <hi>Foul</hi> enough to <hi>blacken</hi> the <hi>Ministry.</hi> To this end they <hi>Vouch</hi> it with <hi>Grave Nod,</hi> and <hi>Solemn Face;</hi> they will talk <hi>Shrewdly</hi> and <hi>Descant</hi> upon it, with a Thousand Pretty Conjectures: They will <hi>Whispher</hi> in your Ear, some <hi>Subtile</hi> and <hi>Notable</hi> observation of Circumstan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces; and with wise and Politick <hi>Forehead,</hi> will suspect Impossible <hi>Plots</hi> upon the Peoples <hi>Liberties, Foresee</hi> unthought of De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signs in the <hi>Court</hi> to that purpose, and <hi>Foretell</hi> strange and Prodigious <hi>Events,</hi> that must necessarily follow: Till by these and the like <hi>Arts,</hi> they make every <hi>false</hi> Report able to walk alone, without the help of Leading-strings, and maintain it self upon its own Credit and Reputation, till the publick <hi>Voice</hi> Confirms it. And then</p>
            <p>You cannot for shame be so <hi>Uncivil,</hi> to Demur upon the Credibility of the <hi>Brute,</hi> when it has received such an Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thoritative <hi>Sanction.</hi> And yet if you would trace these Streams to their Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, you might as well seek the Head of <hi>Nilus,</hi> which tho' it falls with a mighty Torrent, and over-flows <hi>Egypt</hi> with its swelling Streams; you must at last Derive its Original, as some of the Antients have done, from the Mountains in the <hi>Moon.</hi> So if a Man would search for the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thors of these <hi>Malicious,</hi> but <hi>Fabulous Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lations,</hi> he shall be sure to have them Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther'd upon some very Credible Persons <hi>without Names,</hi> who had them from <hi>John a-Nokes,</hi> who had it from <hi>John-a-Stiles,</hi> who had it from <hi>No body.</hi> And if you will observe and Examine all Reports, that bear the Stamp of the <hi>Intermixture,</hi> as <hi>Chrysippus</hi> did the Oracular Lies of <hi>Apollo,</hi> you will find as he did, not One in Five Hundred, that are not apparently Forg'd, and Counterfeit; and therefore I shall take my Leave of them in the Word of a late Poet.
<q>
                  <l>For shame give or'e these sensless Lies,</l>
                  <l>The very Mobb sees the disguise</l>
                  <l>Of your dull Shamms and Fears.</l>
                  <l>In vain You employ them as a blind,</l>
                  <l>While we perceive you have a mind</l>
                  <l>To set us by the Ears.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Britain</hi> which does to <hi>Caesar</hi> own</l>
                  <l>Her Liberty, is wiser grown,</l>
                  <l>Then these stale Arts give o're:</l>
                  <l>We know your wry distorted Faces,</l>
                  <l>Are nought but Tricks to get you Places,</l>
                  <l>And wont be bubbled more.</l>
                  <l>While <hi>Caesar</hi> does the Throne sustain</l>
                  <l>You rail at Monarchy in vain,</l>
                  <l>And idely think to <hi>Rump</hi> it.</l>
                  <l>Tho' faction Common-good pretends</l>
                  <l>To serve their Undermining Ends,</l>
                  <l>We'll Cart their common Strumpet.</l>
               </q>
            </p>
            <p>A careful Shunning of <hi>Imposters,</hi> and Make-bates, and leaving them in the Clouds, they have rais'd, is therefore the duty of every good Subject; lest assisting the <hi>Seditious</hi> in their <hi>Vexatious</hi> contrivances against the Government, you dash upon the Rocks of Offence, and ruin your pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sent Pretensions and future hopes. To a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>void those dangers, Study to be <hi>Quiet,</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue your <hi>Allegiance</hi> to the King, be <hi>Obe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dient</hi> to your <hi>Equals,</hi> and <hi>Civil</hi> to all Men. The practice of these Vertues will procure you <hi>Friends,</hi> and imprint a belief in Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority that you <hi>Deserve</hi> their Favour, 'twould be the best Security of our <hi>Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges,</hi> of Publick <hi>Good,</hi> and Steddy Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. For there is in every Vertuous and Heroick <hi>Soul,</hi> such a sense of his Subjects Love and Duty, that 'twould be an Affront to the Ingenuity of Human Nature, to suppose that a <hi>Prince</hi> can be severe upon a Willing and Obedient People.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:44100:32"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>